<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://hamishrickerby.com" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Hamish Rickerby</title><link>https://hamishrickerby.com</link><description>Hamish Rickerby's blog. I write about software and technology in general.</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 04:43:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2022-02-20-pure-c-atari-st/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2022-02-20-pure-c-atari-st/</link><title>Getting started with Pure-C on the Atari ST</title><description>Getting started with Pure-C on the Atari STTLDR: I found setting up Pure-C to get started with development took me too long (a hour or so on and off to figure it out), so have documented the key points in the process to get up and running. Install, Configure, Code, and Create a Project File are the key steps.</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-06-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-7/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-06-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-7/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 7</title><description>Puzzle 7 - Step 1This puzzle is about calculating the minimum distance to a common integer for a set of integers. OK - the puzzle talks about crab submarines and whales, but that's not that important.</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-06-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-6/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-06-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-6/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 6</title><description>Puzzle 6 - Step 1For todays puzzle we're modelling the lifecycle of fish. The short version is that a fish's timer goes from 8-&gt;0, and after 0 it regenerates itself as 6, and spawns a new 8, increasing the count of fish by 1. In this world, fish are represented as an integer with the value of the int being their timer. To advance a school of fish, we reduce over each of the fish, and when we see one that's a 0, we regenerate it as a 6 and add an 8.</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-05-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-5/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-05-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-5/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 5</title><description>Puzzle 5 - Step 1Todays puzzle is about mapping a bunch of lines that have start/end coordinates, and checking for intersections. We need to count the number of intersections in the map. We are also to only consider horizontal or vertical lines.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-04-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-4/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-04-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-4/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 4</title><description>OCaml - How it's goingI'm feeling much more confident with OCaml now, and becoming familiar with the standard List module. The helper functions I've been developing have had a surprising amount of reuse. Things I've discovered so far:</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-03-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-3/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-03-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-3/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 3</title><description>PrefaceThe OCaml dev tools are doing my head in. I know this must be 100% my fault, but it's so frustrating not being able to do seemingly simple things with the tooling. My main issues are that I can't get a bit of shared code actually shared, and I'm struggling to find a sensible way to structure the multiple days of puzzles into separate sets of code that don't have ridiculous build setups. Anyway, I took some time out and worked on this for a night. I'm backdating these posts for a while...</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-02-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-2/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-02-advent-of-code-2021-puzzle-2/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 2</title><description>Puzzle 2 - Step 1For this puzzle, a sequence of instructions need to be interpreted and change position of a submarine. My solution here was to parse the instructions into a sequence of a custom type that encodes the instructions within the type, and then reduce over that list calculating the position of the submarine. The submarine movements can easily be interpreted via a pattern match.</description><pubDate>Thu, 02 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-01-advent-of-code-2021-setup/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-01-advent-of-code-2021-setup/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021 - Puzzle 1</title><description>One of the issues with getting started with a new language in a time-pressured scenario is setting up environment and tooling. Last year I used VSCode and the ReasonML plugin. It installed relatively straight-forwardly (from what I remember), and supported type hints, and autocompletion. This year I decided I'd setup Emacs, given I use it for everything else. Long story short - what an utter shambles. I tried to follow the installation guide for the Real World OCaml book plus the Prelude OCaml support (I use Prelude with Emacs, due to the great Clojure support it has). It was generally a struggle to get the extensions to handle resolving imports of local files, as well as 3rd party libraries imported via opam. I gave up and went back to VSCode. The plugin setup was straightforward, but I still struggle with being able to actually run a program. I use the utop repl(like) interface to evaluate the statements in my program files, but even that wasn't that simple. Needing to deal with merlin and dune config files just to get my files recognised feels like a bunch of unnecessary complexity. I need to resolve this (and I'd still love to get it all working in emacs), but I can limp along with what I've currently got.Puzzle 1 - Step 1</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-01-advent-of-code-2021/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2021-12-01-advent-of-code-2021/</link><title>Advent of Code 2021</title><description>I try to do at least some of the Advent of Code puzzles each year. Usually I get a few days in then other pressures come up and I have to bail, but I use the puzzles as an opportunity to try out programming languages that are new to me, or ones I want to become more familiar with. Last year I attempted to use OCaml. This went OK for a couple of days, but then we moved internationally and were locked in a hotel room for 2 weeks with young kids, so AoC was the first thing to go out the window.This year I'm looking to use OCaml again to solve the puzzles - I didn't give it a fair shake last year. I've had a bit of experience with ML-style languages via Haskell, so I'm hoping the learning curve isn't too steep.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2020-08-12-javascript-object-compaction/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2020-08-12-javascript-object-compaction/</link><title>Javascript Object Compaction</title><description>I'm working on a feature in BeeCastle at the moment to ingest call data from Microsoft Teams to augment our interaction records. It requires a flexible approach to updating existing records, as with different types of interactions and calls, we get different data.During this process we get a javascript object that might have null or undefined values and these should not be persisted in the database, so we need a way to strip these out. Idiomatic ES6 usage would mean we need to do something like below.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2020-07-26-port-to-cryogen/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2020-07-26-port-to-cryogen/</link><title>Porting blog to cryogen</title><description>Given I'm really digging clojure at the moment, I thought I'd port my blog over from octopress to a clojure based static site generator. I wanted something that supported the same sort of structure, with markdown, and low hassle on getting it running. Cryogen seemed to be the best documented and most modern of the few I could find.The process to port it over was as follows</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2020-07-25-brief-update/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2020-07-25-brief-update/</link><title>"Brief update"</title><description>It's been ages (again).</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-11-02-refactoring-legacy-code-gilded-rose-kata/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-11-02-refactoring-legacy-code-gilded-rose-kata/</link><title>"Refactoring Legacy Code - Gilded Rose Kata"</title><description>Often getting legacy code into a state where you're comfortable making changes to it can be challenging. Legacy code can often have varying levels of quality throughout the codebase, as well as different levels of testing applied to it. I've taken over my fair share of old projects that have no tests, or haven't followed SOLID principles, and understanding how the code works and what it does can be a challenge.The Gilded Rose Kata is an exercise in taking a system that calculates "quality" and expiry dates for items in a shop over time. When you start the Kata, you have a single method that calculates the changes in quality and expiry for the items. The business logic implemented is hard to understand, and features nested if statements with conditionals that feel inverted. You also need to add functionality to support a new item type to the shop to complete the Kata.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-08-25-hard-to-test-code/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-08-25-hard-to-test-code/</link><title>"Refactoring Hard to Test Code"</title><description>As part of the Apprenticeship, I need to create an HTTP server. The purpose of the activity is to create a relatively complex, real-world system with TDD, following SOLID/clean code principles. It's going well so far. There is a FitNesse spec for acceptance tests that the server needs to pass, and I have to create it in Java. I'm getting there.However, I recently found that I was having to jump through some hoops to test my socket connection completion handler, and my mentor suggested this might be a code smell, and that I should look at refactoring the code to make it easier to test. As an aside, I'm using the "new" non-blocking IO socket classes rather than the traditional socket classes, so that multithreading should be simpler as I shouldn't need to manage threadpools.</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-08-20-software-apprenticeships/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-08-20-software-apprenticeships/</link><title>"Software Apprenticeships"</title><description>We have trouble hiring developers. The number of people in Australia with Scala/FP experience is small, and the number of high-quality developers with this experience is even smaller. It also costs us a huge amount of money to hire new staff. Recruiters fees are massive and international candidates attract giant work visa application fees. We typically also only hire Senior Developers with 10+ years commerical experience - people who can lead projects, architect high performing systems, understand not only software developement but all the auxiliary systems as well. Our staff need to be able to be as comfortable with code as they are engaging with clients and stakeholders, presenting at user groups, mentoring, training etc. We need fully rounded software professionals.We can't find them. Or at least, it's becoming harder to find them. We've tried to sort this out on the the demand side - we have open positions with very competitive salaries, in one of the most stunning cities in the world. Our teams work on interesting greenfields projects, with a heavy functional focus. With all this, we're still struggling to find people.</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-08-04-interface-segregation/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-08-04-interface-segregation/</link><title>"Interface Segregation"</title><description>The Interface Segregation principle (part of S.O.L.I.D. is about, very simply, not making subclasses or clients implement interfaces they're not concerned with. Robert Martin calls these 'fat' interfaces. They contain functions or methods that are unrelated to each other, and could be split out into more cohesive interfaces.Forcing clients to implement interfaces they're not concerned with causes unnecessary tight coupling of the client to the interface. If the interface changes, the client needs to reimplement/update itself even if it doesn't use that specific interface function. The result is wasted development effort in maintaining unnecessary code for testing and implementation. This should be avoided.</description><pubDate>Thu, 04 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-07-25-wrapping-3rd-party-code/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-07-25-wrapping-3rd-party-code/</link><title>"Wrapping 3rd Party Code"</title><description>I've been integrating a system I've been developing with a third party service for data synchronisation. We're looking to synchronise tasks out with systems like Pivotal Tracker, Jira, Trello etc, but were unsure which of those systems we would actually use. I'm currently reading Clean Code, and there's a really interesting and relevant chapter on "Boundaries". It covers a similar scenario to what we were facing: Using Third-Party Code.Isolation</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-07-20-function-arguments/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-07-20-function-arguments/</link><title>"Function Arguments"</title><description>In Clean Code it's advocated that the ideal number of arguments for a function is 0. Then, 1, 2, and in very rare cases 3. No functions should take more than 3 arguments.In general, I agree with this. Fewer function arguments = fewer separate parts to understand and should aid with readability (and understanding). There are a couple of complexities though that I'd like to run through here. One is levels of abstraction, and the other is testing.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-07-05-a-small-functional-refactoring-of-some-javascript/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-07-05-a-small-functional-refactoring-of-some-javascript/</link><title>"A small functional refactoring of Javascript"</title><description>I'm working on a web based productivity application at the moment, and have been modifying some old code. This code deals with synchronisation of data with external services, and storage of metadata about the synchronisation of that data. The application had quite a bit of duplication in dealing with this metadata; specifically in extracting data from the stored structures. In the interests of having very DRY Javascript, it was time to refactor.The configuration/metadata structures typically look like</description><pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-06-29-meteor-heroku-and-bcrypt/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-06-29-meteor-heroku-and-bcrypt/</link><title>"Meteor, Heroku, and bcrypt"</title><description>Just had a very frustrating day. Was getting a deployment error on Heroku with a Meteor app I'm making.</description><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-06-27-back-to-basics-editors/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-06-27-back-to-basics-editors/</link><title>"Back to Basics - Editors"</title><description>My boss bought me a copy of the seminal classic The Pragmatic Programmer. It's full of sensible advice for both beginners and experienced software professionals.I have lots of thoughts about the contents of this book but what I'd like to cover is usage of text editors, and specifically becoming proficient with a editor that's typically universally available. I can think of 3 of these for UNIX systems. vi, emacs, and nano.</description><pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-06-23-reading-not-reading/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-06-23-reading-not-reading/</link><title>"Reading not Reading"</title><description>I recently finished a book called Apprenticeship Patterns (more on why later) and one of the things it suggested is keeping an online list of books you read, and books you want to read. So here is mine.http://hamishrickerby.com/books/</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-05-17-brief-update/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2016-05-17-brief-update/</link><title>"Brief update"</title><description>It's been ages.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-09-27-why-ive-taken-a-full-time-job/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-09-27-why-ive-taken-a-full-time-job/</link><title>"Why I've taken a full time job"</title><description>I've relapsed. I swore I'd never do it again, but I have. I've accepted a full time job.I'm not in it for the money</description><pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-03-02-1000km-february/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-03-02-1000km-february/</link><title>"1000km - February"</title><description>Progress has been a bit slower this month. Short month, very hot here, and new baby all contributed to slowing progress down. Oh, in other news, we now have a baby!  Exciting.190km complete at end of Feb, which leaves me with a 30km buffer. The last graph was a little incorrect too - Numbers only puts dates correctly (in relative terms) on the x-axis if the graph type is a scatterplot. Dumb. The new graph below is correct.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-01-31-1000km-january/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-01-31-1000km-january/</link><title>"1000km - January"</title><description>Progress on the 1000km is good so far. 109km run in Jan, and I'm sticking to the 10km distance per run. Weight is also starting to fall, which is great because I'm about 9kg heavier than I should be.Because I'm also a nerd (and if you're reading my blog, you probably are too), here's a graph marking progress. Grey line is what I need to run to get to 1000km this year. Any blue higher than the grey line is kms in the bank for a rainy day.</description><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-01-23-meteor/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-01-23-meteor/</link><title>"Meteor"</title><description>A couple of days ago I received an email from meetup.com about meetups that I might be interested in. Usually this is full of crap I don't care about, like mothers groups or salsa dancing, but this most recent mail featured an intriguing group called "Meteor Melbourne - a better way to build apps". So, I looked into it.Meteor is a framework based on node.js that allows you to write responsive, reactive, real-time web applications in javascript on both the client and server side. I've always considered javascript as a toy language - I think this opinion comes from my first interaction with JavaScript waaaaaay back in the late 90's (I think it was somewhere between '96 and '98), when all it was really used for was alert boxes and tic-tac-toe implementations. However, I've recently been doing a lot of work for clients with Parse and their "cloud code" functionality, taking some logic out of mobile apps and running it on the Parse servers - and you use JavaScript to do this. They promoted use of Promises, and I've been doing a lot with RAC in iPhone apps, so this functional style is something I'm familiar with and like. I also have a friend who is helping a mate out on a startup, who is looking at some serious "enterprise" functionality implemented with server-side javascript, so I thought it was maybe time to seriously look at this thing too, and I checked it out.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-01-20-2014/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2014-01-20-2014/</link><title>"2014"</title><description>I'm not one for new years resolutions, but there are a couple of things I'd like to achieve this year.</description><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2013-03-22-medical-regulation-and-apps/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2013-03-22-medical-regulation-and-apps/</link><title>"Medical Regulation and Apps"</title><description>Yesterday I read an article in Venture Beat covering part of a series of hearings US Congress is holding on regulation of health and medical apps on smartphone and tablet devices. My significantly paraphrased version of the article is that the FDA are unsure if and how health apps should be regulated, and that representatives from the "app" industry are pushing for no regulation for consumer facing apps.I have a slightly different take on this. To me, the question is simple (and what is driving health authorities globally to address this issue): can health apps be considered to be medical devices?</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2013-02-23-drying-out-objective-c-identification/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2013-02-23-drying-out-objective-c-identification/</link><title>"DRYing out Objective-C - Identification"</title><description>I have a large objective-c codebase I've been working on with a client for over a year now. The application started off as a prototype, and transitioned into a demo client, and is currently undergoing modifications for security/penetration testing and commercialization. Initially for the protoype and demo, the objective was to get a working application as quickly as possible - speed of initial development was the key. With the current change in focus to a more productized codebase, and improving maintainability as part of that, I decided I'd actively go hunting for areas in the application that can be tidied up, and particularly, looking for duplicate segments of code and eliminating them where feasible.DRY - or Don't Repeat Yourself - is (according to Wikipedia) a principle is stated as "Every piece of knowledge must have a single, unambiguous, authoritative representation within a system." ... When the DRY principle is applied successfully, a modification of any single element of a system does not require a change in other logically unrelated elements. Additionally, elements that are logically related all change predictably and uniformly, and are thus kept in sync.</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-10-25-the-value-of-contracting/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-10-25-the-value-of-contracting/</link><title>"The Value of Contracting"</title><description>Very unexpectedly, for the past few weeks I've been working with a Digital Agency here in Melbourne on a sports-themed iPhone app for a very large client of theirs (a worldwide media brand). I was called in at the 11th hour to work with two  other developers (both experienced iOS and ruby contractors), and I knew within the first hour there that the project was going to be a significant challenge. The project had unrealistically tight timelines and a lack of testing and testing platforms/data sets available.Needless to say, it was an interesting experience. In my previous full time jobs I've never worked as a developer, and with my current company all projects to date have been single developer projects.  But I definitely found the whole experience really rewarding. It reminded me of the time I was a manager in a large digital agency myself, only there it was me cracking the whip to get development in on time, rather than having the whip cracked on me. :-)
(It also meant I had to get dressed and leave the house to work!)</description><pubDate>Thu, 25 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-07-14-99-problems-but-haskell-aint-one/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-07-14-99-problems-but-haskell-aint-one/</link><title>"99 Problems (but Haskell ain't one)"</title><description>Back in the late 90's I took COSC 122 at the University of Canterbury. We had to learn functional programming as part of that course - HUGS (it's based on Haskell 98). It never really clicked with me - for some reason my brain would just not understand functional programming.{% img /images/tumblr_leretcb0Sa1qfawn6o1_500.jpg %}</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-07-06-updating-a-uitableview-without-calling-reloaddata/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-07-06-updating-a-uitableview-without-calling-reloaddata/</link><title>"Updating a UITableView without calling reloadData"</title><description>For a new app I've been working on for the past few days I wanted to a nice "inline" way of gathering data from the user. Typically, if I've needed to have a user put in more than a single line of text, I would have popped the user to a different screen that has a UITextView as the sole point of focus, get them to type in the data, and then have them navigate back and have the data appear within a tableview.For this new app, I wanted them to be able to enter large amounts of text inline within a cell of a tableview. This also means that the cell would have to dynamically grow and shrink, as the user is entering the data. The UITextView (where the user is entering the data) would need to resize itself based on the users input, as well as the UITableViewCell that contains the text view, and have the UITableView adjust on the fly to the users input.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 Jul 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-06-04-core-data-migrations-and-large-data-sets/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-06-04-core-data-migrations-and-large-data-sets/</link><title>"Core Data Migrations and Large Data Sets"</title><description>I recently updated Moving Van (you should buy it now!) and published the new version in the app store late last week. It was a substantial update to the application - it had a completely new UI with custom interface controls, as well as a whole stack of features that customers had been asking for - things like room autocompletion, saving images to camera roll, more export options, moving items between boxes etc.As part of this update, I also remodelled the Core Data entities that power the application. The initial model that was used was, let's say, a little naïve in terms of the way that the stored data would impact performance of the application. It stored an image on an item as binary data within the Item entity itself, which in retrospect was a terrible idea because of table view performance. The new version split out the image to a separate entity, which means that when the Item entity loads, the image doesn't get loaded unless explicitly needed because of the faulting behaviour of Core Data and entity relationships.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-05-19-uisearchbars-uitextfield/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-05-19-uisearchbars-uitextfield/</link><title>"UISearchBar's UITextField"</title><description>For an update that I'm making to Moving Van (you should buy it now!) I need to customise the font that is displayed in a UISearchBar's text field. The search bar does not actually expose it's UITextField property, but because the search bar is a UIView, it's trivial to access the field to allow customisation.</description><pubDate>Sat, 19 May 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-04-30-ibooks-crashing/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-04-30-ibooks-crashing/</link><title>"iBooks Crashing?"</title><description>I'm having a bit of a play with iBooks today, and some 3D model stuff. iBooks has, for me, always crashed when displaying 3D models. I don't have a jailbroken iPad, so it's not a DRM issue (at least not one caused by that). To tell you the truth, I'm not sure what the cause is. But, I do have a fix!</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-04-10-housekeeping/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-04-10-housekeeping/</link><title>"Housekeeping"</title><description>I currently have around thirteen or so applications developed for iOS that are live in the App Store (and one in development). I have one Mac application (and one in development). I also run an online accounting system, two T-Shirt stores, a postcard printing and shipping business, and a web hosting and technical website build business.That's a lot of stuff for one guy to maintain. Because of the amount of time I have available to dedicate to each, it can be a long time before I get to maintain or market any particular application or service that I've developed. Because of this, the services don't change often, they underperform in the marketplace, and over time the revenues have been decreasing.</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-04-05-unit-test-code-coverage-with-xcode-4-dot-3-2/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-04-05-unit-test-code-coverage-with-xcode-4-dot-3-2/</link><title>"Unit Test Code Coverage with Xcode 4.3.2"</title><description>I upgraded to Xcode 4.3.2 and this seemed to break unit tests on iOS for me.The error that was being reported was:
Test rig '/Applications/Xcode.app/.../iPhoneSimulator.platform/.../otest' exited abnormally with code 134 (it may have crashed).</description><pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-01-26-continuous-integration-and-ios/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-01-26-continuous-integration-and-ios/</link><title>"Continuous Integration and iOS"</title><description>The client project I'm currently working on is quite large. There are over 90 different screens required in the application, and regression testing all of these, with the different data variants and scenarios is not something I'd like to attempt by hand, and is not something I would expect my client to pay for me (or anyone for that matter) to do. Both unit and application tests can be automated, and I figured that this was something that I should do for this project to ensure changes I introduce don't break existing functionality, and any bugs found won't be introduced.To solve this challenge I have introduced a Continuous Integration (CI) server to my workflow. My goals were to have unit and application tests automatically executed when an commit is made to a specific branch in a (local) git repository, and if both of these phases are successful, have the application packaged up, ready for distribution. I also wanted this successful build to be deployed on a daily basis to TestFlight so my client (and any other human testers in the future) could pick it up on their devices. I also wanted code coverage reporting, for both the unit and application tests, so I can see what parts of the application logic and screen flows are actually being tested to give me a level of confidence that the right stuff is getting the attention. The application tests also needed to be executed in a headless manner - I don't have a physically separate machine (or VM) to run the CI server in, so I don't want the simulator popping up and distracting me.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-01-26-on-hold-dot-dot-dot-temporarily/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2012-01-26-on-hold-dot-dot-dot-temporarily/</link><title>"On hold...temporarily"</title><description>I had some great news last week. A previous client asked me to submit a quote for the full version of a prototype iOS app I had created for him last year. I submitted the proposal, but had assumed he was using it to benchmark other application development companies against. To my surprise, he accepted my proposal, and awarded me the work. It's a substantial piece of work, and technically quite challenging. It also has the potential to be a big innovation on the space it's in, so is exciting from that aspect too.So, I accepted. The issue for me is that this puts my other project on hold for a few months. However, income is good, and this will let me work for longer on my project after I'm done, so it's a positive move.</description><pubDate>Thu, 19 Jan 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-12-29-user-experience-books/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-12-29-user-experience-books/</link><title>"User Experience Books"</title><description>As I alluded to in a previous post, things like User Experience, Human Computer Interaction, and Graphic Design are not my fortes. All my professional software experience until I started iOS development was either in developing (~2 years) or designing/architecting (9+ years) large scale telecommunications software systems (specifically BSS and OSS systems if you're interested). These sorts of systems do not have pretty user interfaces - there is no need to provide them. In fact, the majority of systems I have designed only have human interactions with back-office operators who are Unix system administrators - the main "user" of the system would typically be another system.The users of my new software will be proper "end-users". People who do not use computers for a job. People who are unsure, or even wary about computers for fear of breaking them. People who do not know commands like kill -9 when something isn't working, or even how to drive a CLI.</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-12-22-sandboxing/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-12-22-sandboxing/</link><title>"Sandboxing"</title><description>Since the last post and this one, we've moved 10500 miles (that's nearly 17,000 kilometres!) and only yesterday got all our utilities sorted out, meaning that I've basically been offline (bar mobile phone for the past 3 weeks). Melbourne is fantastic. I really like it here.Anyway, I've been doing a little bit of work on my application, mostly completion of the requirements, data model, and competitor analysis, as well as reading up a bit on UX and Mac way of doing things (I'll probably cover this in another entry), and most recently have been prototyping some code that I thought would be particularly tricky.</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-11-27-im-on-a-list/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-11-27-im-on-a-list/</link><title>"I'm on a list"</title><description>Yesterday I attended onedotzero at the British Film Institute. I was invited by alphalabs.cc to their launch event, in conjunction with Microsoft and Nokia.It was pitched as "an experiment that merges technology and the arts" - and this blend (to me at least) is intriguing. Since I discovered "creative coding" I have been fascinated by the experimental applications that fit in this space, so didn't want to miss out on this event. I have no idea how I got an invite... I wonder if it was because I'm a Nokia dev member, or because I have previously been active on the oF forums, or maybe I was just very lucky.</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-11-07-case-and-requirements-management/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-11-07-case-and-requirements-management/</link><title>"CASE and Requirements Management"</title><description>I've started the feature &amp; function planning for my application - or really, I've started to identify the requirements for it. I'm starting by evaluating existing applications in the marketplace, considering the functions they support, the data they collect, and how the user navigates through the application. So far, I have about 300 screenshots from various applications,  strewn all over the floor of my office, and 4 coloured pens for me to mark up the screenshots. The colours refer to the following areas of requirements or commentary.</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-28-6-&lt;-36/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-28-6-&lt;-36/</link><title>"6 &lt; 36"</title><description>Three years eh? I'm planning 6 months.I guess the key difference here is that I'm not planning on having any employees at 6 months. I don't plan on being able to replace the lucrative contracting I've been doing either. In fact, I don't really expect any sales at 6 months.</description><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-27-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-27-start-with-the-end-in-mind/</link><title>"Start With the End in Mind"</title><description>The product I'm going to make could be very large. There are loads of features it could support, but one of the first jobs I need to do is decide what it must do for a first release, that delivers value to customers. I've started getting in touch with small business people that I know to understand what they would value in such a product, but there are just so many diverse suggestions, even when I've given them initial scope for what I think the first release could do. I find myself thinking "that's easy, that'll only add a day or two" to certain features, but I'm fairly confident when it comes time to design these things, the duration and complexity will explode.One thing that is common in pharmaceuticals (@mrsrickerby works in that industry, so I have a little understanding of how things work there) is that a "Core Data Sheet" - aka a core product specification - is written before and during development and testing of the product . This document specifies needs and wants which at the end of each phase of development are used as the yardstick to make go/no-go decisions. For example, if you want to show a 5% improvement in some disease state but your phase 2 study doesn't achieve this, you stop development. It is a living document which, as data is collected, the actual product profile is documented which ultimately becomes the package insert (the bit of paper in the box).</description><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-24-work-plans/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-24-work-plans/</link><title>"Work Plans"</title><description>As part of moving to Melbourne, I need to decide what I'm going to do to generate income. Traditionally I would either take a Senior Solutions Architect or Enterprise Architect job in a telco, or look for an equivalent role contracting. I think that's not going to be the case quite yet.After talking to @mrsrickerby at the pub about this (all our big decisions are made at the pub), we collectively decided that I am going to continue to work for myself. Not as a contractor though, but trying to create a sustainable software company, that is more than a 1 man band.</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-22-big-changes/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2011-10-22-big-changes/</link><title>"Big Changes"</title><description>Big changes are taking place. My wife @mrsrickerby and I have decided that we are going to move to Australia. Well, not so much that we are going to move to Australia, more like we are moving. At the start of December 2011. To a city I have never been to before. Melbourne.The rationale behind the move is that we would both like to be closer to our families. We're both from New Zealand, and the UK for us was only ever temporary. We've been here 5 years, and it's time to move on. We've had a good time here. Reading is the place I've spent the 3rd most time in, only being beaten by Auckland (if you count living in a hotel in Sydney for 9 months as living in Auckland), and Christchurch where I spent just over 21 years.</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-07-23-iphone-ipad-localizations-regions/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-07-23-iphone-ipad-localizations-regions/</link><title>'iPhone &amp; iPad (iOS) Localizations and Regions '</title><description>Recently I have been doing some localizations of an iOS app from English (US) to English (UK). The iPhone development guides from Apple describe how to support multiple languages (such as English, German, Japanese), but fail to describe how to support multiple variants of a single language. By this I mean support support for US English, English, NZ English, AU English. The word I needed to regionalize was Behavior (or Behaviour, depending where you come from).In the Apple Developer Library, it explicitly states that for MacOS applications take both the Language and Regional preferences of the user into account, but only look at the preferred language on iOS - Support for Internationalization.  This means that a single variant per language is supported.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-03-04-moving-van/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-03-04-moving-van/</link><title>Moving Van</title><description>Yesterday when I came home Moving Van's sales were up. I was a bit surprised as I hadn't done any specific marketing for the app, and what was really odd is that they were only up for the UK.  A little investigation and I discover that Moving Van has been featured as "New and Noteworthy" in the iTunes Store UK.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 04 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-02-08-ad-from-digg/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-02-08-ad-from-digg/</link><title>Ad from Digg</title><description>Seriously, WTF?  I assume it's some sort of movie tie-in...</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-01-07-calculate-age-in-objective-c/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2010-01-07-calculate-age-in-objective-c/</link><title>'Calculate age in objective-c '</title><description>For an iPhone application I'm developing for a client I need to capture the birthdate of a user, and then show their age on a profile screen. I went looking for a function to help with this simple and tedious task, but couldn't find any example code that could be lifted to help me, so I rolled my own.  Here is what I made, steal as you see fit.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-20-iphone-camera-overlays-iphonearkit/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-20-iphone-camera-overlays-iphonearkit/</link><title>iPhone Camera Overlays + iphonearkit</title><description>Today I have been hacking away on the iphonearkit source available at github and have incorporated the ARGeoViewController as an overlay over a ImagePickerController with the camera as the source (which was introduced with iPhone OS 3.1).  Results below.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-20-augmented-reality-hello-world/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-20-augmented-reality-hello-world/</link><title>Augmented Reality - Hello World</title><description>I've recently discovered augmented reality. After I saw my first "virtual business card" application I was hooked.  I've been doing a lot of reading and experimenting with software over the past 2 days, and have got ARToolkit working here.  Here are some shots of the obligitory "cube over marker" demo.  I would post a video, but my screen capture software and AR software = a really poor frame rate and substandard video :-(</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-17-no-i-dont-agree/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-17-no-i-dont-agree/</link><title>No, I don't agree</title><description>Tough luck - the box is un-uncheckable.I guess it's one way to make sure that people accept your terms &amp; conditions - force them to.  One less click.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-11-kit-quiz-uk/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-09-11-kit-quiz-uk/</link><title>'Kit Quiz: UK'</title><description>&lt;shameless self promotion&gt;My 4th iPhone application was approved yesterday by Apple, and it launches in the iTunes store today.  It's called Kit Quiz: UK and is a UK team based football (soccer) shirt quiz game.  It features over 130 shirts from UK football teams, and will have more added shortly.  There are 3 modes of gameplay, from the practise model "Friendly" to a time challenge "Blitz".</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-08-15-passenger-ruby-on-rails-php-on-osx/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-08-15-passenger-ruby-on-rails-php-on-osx/</link><title>Passenger (Ruby on Rails) + PHP on OSX</title><description>I've spent the last hour or so trying various things out to get passenger and PHP to play nicely together on my mac under OS X (Leopard) and apache2.The situation I was finding was that PHP apps would run, but only if you explicitly call the script (ie index.php) rather than just the directory.  If you called the directory, passenger would take over and give me a rails routing error.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-08-07-123456789/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-08-07-123456789/</link><title>'123456789'</title><description>Today in the UK the time hit 12:34:56 7/8/9.  Not exciting for everyone I guess, but it won't happen again for another 100 years.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-08-04-undefined-method-rewind-and-rails-2-3-3/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-08-04-undefined-method-rewind-and-rails-2-3-3/</link><title>Undefined method rewind and rails 2.3.3</title><description>Today I updated a project I'm working on from rails 2.2.something to 2.3.3.  Then, I started getting the following wacky error.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-07-31-ussd-codes-on-iphone/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-07-31-ussd-codes-on-iphone/</link><title>USSD Codes on iPhone</title><description>makeuseof.com have recently posted about 11 cool iPhone keypad codes - these are special codes (known as USSD codes) that send messages via the signalling channel direct to the core of a mobile operators network.  These codes are nothing new, they have been around for years and years.  They are also not generally universal (there are some standard, but they provide relatively boring functionality).  Different networks can enable different functionality on different codes.The codes can do boring things like retrieve your divert status from the network, return your IMEI or perhaps ICCID, but they can also interact with specialised applications driven via USSD Gateways to return useful information and execute transactions.  These are applications that are sent specific codes by an operators core network, perform some processing on the data received, and return a response.  Things that are non-standard that are enabled by USSD Gateways are services such as USSD-based prepay balance retrieval, USSD-topup, or interactions with NGIN features to alter a network based service.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-07-30-yahoo-and-microsoft-micro-hoo-or-bingy/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-07-30-yahoo-and-microsoft-micro-hoo-or-bingy/</link><title>Yahoo and Microsoft - Micro-hoo, or Bingy!</title><description>The recent deal announced between Microsoft and Yahoo strikes me as odd.I understand that they are looking to create a competitor to Google in both search and advertising, but the "price paid" seems very high - at least on the part of Yahoo.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-07-29-itunes-connect-now-has-keywords/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-07-29-itunes-connect-now-has-keywords/</link><title>iTunes Connect now has keywords</title><description>Apple have added an extra attribute to applications on iTunes store - keywords.You can configure your keywords with the "Edit Information" link against the application.  SendIt4.me (iTMS) has already been updated :-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-05-11-my-first-iphone-app-approved-finally/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-05-11-my-first-iphone-app-approved-finally/</link><title>My first iPhone app approved - finally</title><description>Send real postcards to your family and friends with SendIt4.me, now available as an iPhone client.  The application is 100% free and each postcard you send will cost $2USD.  The postcards can be sent anywhere in the world, and postage time is dependent on your international and local mail services (they are posted from the US, so if you live there you should get it quicker).Download now!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 11 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-03-20-feedzirra/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-03-20-feedzirra/</link><title>Feedzirra</title><description>Feedzirra is an RSS feed fetching and parsing library that I quite like.  For a project I'm working on with a mate we need to be able to parse and receive updates from (potentially) a large number of RSS feeds.  Feedzirra seemed the ticket, but didn't have support for itunes style RSS feeds - so I added it.This was basically my first (well, second, but that wasn't public) go with github, and first contribution to an open source project.  Paul Dix accepted my code, and I'm oddly excited about it all.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-03-02-esta-and-confusion/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-03-02-esta-and-confusion/</link><title>ESTA and Confusion</title><description>I went to look at the ESTA website today as my girlfriend needs to apply for one of these authorisations to be allowed to travel to the US.The website was very intimidating, and confusing.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-02-26-dealing-with-semantichacker-in-ruby/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-02-26-dealing-with-semantichacker-in-ruby/</link><title>Dealing with SemanticHacker in Ruby</title><description>I'm having a bit of a play with SemanticHacker at the moment, seeing what their service thinks of some text I'm poking at it.  To make this a bit simpler I created a small ruby lib that wraps their API to make my life a little easier.  And hopefully it'll make someone elses life easier - enjoy.(It requires hpricot for XML parsing - make sure it's installed)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-02-20-installing-f2c-on-a-mac/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-02-20-installing-f2c-on-a-mac/</link><title>Installing f2c on a mac</title><description>I have recently had to install f2c on my mac to convert Fortran to C code - for the gory details about this library check http://www.netlib.org/f2c/f2c.pdfAlso, don't ask why I'm installing this - lets just say there is some maths that needs doing, and fortran has the libraries to help with it.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-02-01-cocos2d-iphone-blocking-touch-events/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-02-01-cocos2d-iphone-blocking-touch-events/</link><title>cocos2d-iphone blocking touch events</title><description>The game development is going well so far.  From yesterday when I knew NOTHING about game development I've managed to figure out how to use sprites, labels, timed actions, sequenced actions, scenes and layers with cocos2d-iphone.I did hit a strange error though.  On the simulator the touch events were working correctly - screens transitioning, sprite/label touches generating events and triggering animation and so on.  On the actual device the story was quite different.  My menu items were triggering correctly, but no subsequent touch events were doing anything on the phone.  When the application exited (home button) all the touch events were then passed through as I could see them all fly up the screen in the console.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-01-31-error-on-line-1987/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-01-31-error-on-line-1987/</link><title>error on line 1987</title><description>I am having a bit of a play with the cocos2d game engine for iPhone and encountered a very strange error in the console - I don't believe it's at all related to the game engine itself, so it's just coincidence that I was trying something new out.error while killing target (killing anyway): warning: error on line 1987 of "/SourceCache/gdb/gdb-962/src/gdb/macosx/macosx-nat-inferior.c" in function "macosx_kill_inferior_safe": (os/kern) failure (0x5x)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-01-04-user-preferences-on-iphone/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-01-04-user-preferences-on-iphone/</link><title>User Preferences on iPhone</title><description>Getting and setting user preferences on iPhone is pretty darn easy.  I was looking for a way to automagically store a users email address between different application sessions, and found the linked tutorial immensely helpful (iphonedevelopertips.com).I needed to store a string (NSString object actually) however, and the tutorial didn't help me with that. The NSUserDefaults object has dedicated methods for storing and retrieving BOOL, float, and NSInteger values.  It also has a setObject:forKey: method - which is what I ended up using.  The setObject method handles data of types NSData, NSString, NSDate, NSArray or NSDictitionary - making it incredibly useful indeed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 04 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-01-02-last-days-woolworths/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2009-01-02-last-days-woolworths/</link><title>'Last Days: Woolworths'</title><description>Went into Woolies here in Reading a couple of days ago to see what was left on the shelves. They truly are selling everything. People were literally buying the shelves the remaining products were sitting on. I also saw them offering the tills for £150 - considered getting one so I could play shopkeeper, but no.Some pics of the carnage</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-12-27-zazzle-discount-vouchers-codes/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-12-27-zazzle-discount-vouchers-codes/</link><title>Zazzle discount vouchers / codes</title><description>I received a package I ordered from Zazzle today and it contained some discount vouchers that I won't be using.  Codes below - tell me if they don't work so I can update the post to show they are gone.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-12-13-memory-management-in-objective-c/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-12-13-memory-management-in-objective-c/</link><title>Memory Management in Objective-C</title><description>I was having some issues with Memory Management and dealloc'ing objects (and subsequently crashing software) and found the following resources very useful:</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 13 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-12-10-car-tries-to-climb-fence-in-reading/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-12-10-car-tries-to-climb-fence-in-reading/</link><title>Car tries to climb fence in Reading</title><description>This is what I saw on my way home from work today.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-11-09-dodgy-supermarkets/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-11-09-dodgy-supermarkets/</link><title>Dodgy Supermarkets</title><description>Sainsburys have X-rated cereals apparently. I didn't see any actual X-rated material though.&lt;img class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-264" title="Adult Cereals" src="http://hamishrickerby.com/wp-content/uploads/2008/11/img_0095-225x300.jpg" alt="Sign saying "Adult Cereals"" width="225" height="300" /&gt;</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-11-06-what-i-like-about-working-at-my-companys-offices/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-11-06-what-i-like-about-working-at-my-companys-offices/</link><title>What I like about working at my companys offices</title><description>On client sites I don't get a desk phone. I like desk phones.In newbury Waitrose has a poor selection of sushi. In Canary Wharf there is an itsu. I like sushi.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-11-04-linkedin-iphone-application/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-11-04-linkedin-iphone-application/</link><title>LinkedIn iPhone Application</title><description>Old news, but new for me today.LinkedIn have released an iPhone app. I'm a big fan and user of their app, and I think keeping up to date has just become a lot easier with this iPhone app.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-26-firefox-303-and-500-internal-errors-with-javascript/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-26-firefox-303-and-500-internal-errors-with-javascript/</link><title>Firefox 3.0.3 and 500 Internal Errors with Javascript</title><description>I had a very confusing situation today with a multipart form that was for uploading a picture to a new web service I'm working on.In Safari the form upload worked. Even in Internet Explorer 6 the form upload worked (after I fixed the dodgy MIME-type that IE passes through for JPG images - image/pjpeg for those interested).</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-17-great-job-title/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-17-great-job-title/</link><title>Great job title</title><description>Group Manager of Enforcementand it's not what you're thinking...</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-11-underacheiving/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-11-underacheiving/</link><title>Underacheiving</title><description>Carling has a campaign here - "probably the best beer in the world". I found tonight they have been beaten in terms of finding marketing phrases that suck.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-10-is-it-just-a-kiwi-thing/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-10-10-is-it-just-a-kiwi-thing/</link><title>Is it just a kiwi thing?</title><description>Air New Zealand has recently launched a new campaign.  What makes me chuckle, and angry is the folllowing ad:</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-09-18-nz-dont-get-no-respect/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-09-18-nz-dont-get-no-respect/</link><title>NZ don't get no respect!</title><description>I've recently transferred some funds internationally.  To do this I needed a special account code so that the bank I'm sending money to know which of the accounts they hold should receive it.  This number is a conventional looking account number, prefixed with a country code, and a checksum value.  There is also a website that checks them - http://www.apacs.org.uk/payments_industry/ibans_5.htmlPutting in a country that they can't check the actual account number for causes their little javascript application to unleash a serious dissing.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-09-02-people-as-assets/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-09-02-people-as-assets/</link><title>People as assets</title><description>I was sitting at a desk last week and overheard a man yelling down a phone to someone else that "People aren't an asset.  They don't appear on a balance sheet". I agree with that view - not because of the strict accounting definition of an asset, but because of what I believe people in companies should mean (either consciously or subconsciously) when humans are called assets.Companies refer to humans as assets for 2 reasons.  (1) To make employees feel good and (2) because of the value they create for and contribute to the business.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 02 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-09-01-on-getting-a-site-into-google-abridged/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-09-01-on-getting-a-site-into-google-abridged/</link><title>on getting a site into google. Abridged.</title><description>me: Countees isn't in google yetsomeone else: You have to put it in there?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-30-amazons-mp3-offer/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-30-amazons-mp3-offer/</link><title>Amazons MP3 offer</title><description>I got an email yesterday from Amazon.com about the Verve's new album Forth.  They were offering me a free, DRM free download of their latest song "Love is Noise".  Having not heard anything out of the Verve for a while I was interested, and free is a pretty good price so I went to download.The first thing I was unimpressed with was the Amazon.com downloader they tried to install on my machine.  I understand that some people may not understand how to add MP3s to iTunes, but the "skip this step" link to me was not in an intuitive place.  So, I accidentally downloaded it, went back to the page, then found the skip link.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-22-iphone-202-software-update/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-22-iphone-202-software-update/</link><title>iPhone 2.0.2 Software Update</title><description>Apple released this update a day or two ago.  I installed it yesterday morning.Unhappy customer.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-20-dumb-things-company-websites-dont-do/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-20-dumb-things-company-websites-dont-do/</link><title>Dumb Things Company Websites Dont, But Should Do</title><description>Opening hours. I want them on every physical stores, restaurants, and bars website. They do good store locators in the UK, I guess it's because postcodes are everywhere, everyone knows them and they identify a very small area (a street, or part of a street). How come stores, when thinking about the data on their store locator, don't include opening hours. Address and phone are always there, but when I'm going home on the train I want to know if my local stores will still be open when I get there.Oh well, no spending at that particular store tonight.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-15-radiant-cms-tutorial-custom-javascript-in-admin-pages/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-15-radiant-cms-tutorial-custom-javascript-in-admin-pages/</link><title>Radiant CMS Tutorial - Custom Javascript in Admin Pages</title><description>At the moment I'm working on a fairly complex extension for Radiant CMS. In creating the administrative pages I want to use a javascript library that is not distributed with the core radiant code. This post will describe how to implement your own extension that can use an external javascript library, without playing around with any of the core radiant files to inject the javascript into the administrative layout.It's actually really easy to do.  If you haven't created a Radiant extension before I'd recommend following this tutorial on the Radiant wiki.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-05-googles-ajax-libraries-api/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-08-05-googles-ajax-libraries-api/</link><title>Google's AJAX Libraries API</title><description>This might be old news (released end of May, I'm soooo behind the times), but Google are supporting hosting for popular javascript libraries, and they are promoting people using their copies of the libraries rather than hosting their own.  I only just found this out, and I think it's pretty coolhttp://code.google.com/apis/ajaxlibs/</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-30-there-is-a-better-way-and-its-about-time-i-started-showing-people/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-30-there-is-a-better-way-and-its-about-time-i-started-showing-people/</link><title>There is a better way (and it's about time I started showing people)</title><description>Recent blog post from 37 signals - What you expect from clients is what you getIt's interesting - I see exactly the same thing in organisations I've worked for and with (I mainly deal with very large multi-national companies).  One organisation in particular has a long history of process, and gates, and hoops, and requirements, and documentation, and review periods, and signoffs.  Those things aren't necessarily bad, but this organisation also has a long history of burning money, and not delivering anything.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-28-invisibleshield-discount-codes/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-28-invisibleshield-discount-codes/</link><title>invisibleSHIELD discount codes</title><description>I ordered an invisibleSHIELD from zagg.com for my iPhone 3G today - and they gave me 2x discount codes for 20% off in their online store.  I don't need them, so I'm posting them below.  If they don't work (they are one use only) let me know and I'll post a comment saying they're gone.4w5vfh</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-24-lost-followers-on-twitter/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-24-lost-followers-on-twitter/</link><title>Lost followers on Twitter</title><description>Twitter seems to be having some issues, well, more issues than normal.  I was surprised to not get any updates on Twitterrific on my iphone today, so though I'd check out what was going down on their site.  It appears that I've lost all of the people I was following, and all of my followers.  A quick check with some of the followers as well, and they've lost all their contacts.Come on Twitter, what's going on?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-22-wordpress-for-iphone/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-22-wordpress-for-iphone/</link><title>Wordpress for iphone</title><description>This morning I saw on the iTunes store that Automattic had their wordpress iPhone application released. I promptly downloaded and installed it onto my new phone.  I'm writing this entry on it now and it seems pretty good. You can upload photos but I think writing HTML will be a bit of a pain, but for a quick blog post it seems to do the job. I say if you have an iPhone and a wordpress based blog then this is a good application to have, and the price can't be beat.Update: uploading a photo causes my iPhone to crash. I'll try again :-S Hmmm, it worked that time.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-22-not-all-software-is-created-equal/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-07-22-not-all-software-is-created-equal/</link><title>Not all software is created equal</title><description>The types of companies I (used to) work for and (now) consult to,  love release management.  At least their IT people do.For those who are not in the know, check out the following 2 resources for a bit of background</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-06-14-wordpress-migration-again/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-06-14-wordpress-migration-again/</link><title>Wordpress migration - again</title><description>I've updated Wordpress, AND migrated my two blogs together to be one, again.I've also tried to support the existing feeds - so I've got a couple of permanent redirects in the .htaccess files to sort them out.  So, if your feeds don't work anymore, your crappy feedreader doesn't support the HTTP specification correctly.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-06-14-redesigned-glimmer-design/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-06-14-redesigned-glimmer-design/</link><title>Redesigned Glimmer Design</title><description>I spent the day reworking Glimmer Design.  I always intended to - the template I had on there was good, but not quite what I was after.  I had a think last week about what I'd like the site to look like, and I made it today. </description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-05-31-mnemonic-password-generator-a-la-ruby/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-05-31-mnemonic-password-generator-a-la-ruby/</link><title>Mnemonic Password Generator - a la Ruby</title><description>I wanted to have a mnenonic password generator for a little application that I'm writing in ruby, and couldn't find one out there.  So, I rolled my own.  Actually, it's a knock-off of a Python one I found, but that doesn't really matter.Do with this what you will.  Hope it's useful to someone.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-03-18-podcasts/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-03-18-podcasts/</link><title>Podcasts</title><description>I've been struggling to find podcasts that I really dig.  Redmonk radio lost me as a listener.  I thought their early episodes (up to around 40 or so) were great.  A good mix of strategy, business, and IT - in a general sense.  I'm quite an enterprise focussed generalist, so that really appealed to me.  However, recently they have released the RIA and IT Management podcasts, and they are not for me at all - so I unsubscribed.I went looking last night for some new podcasts in iTunes that might appeal to me.  I found a couple, but am still left unimpressed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-03-06-flash/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-03-06-flash/</link><title>Flash!</title><description>I'm doing a bit of Flash work for a mate who is setting up a website to host video.  One of the problems I just solved was how to get some text to flow around an image.  I was hoping there would be some sort of way to make a textfield of arbitrary shape (with vectors or something) because I really wanted an L shaped textfield, so I could place an image in the upper left corner, but sadly, they are just rectangles.  I found this post though, and the solution was so simple.Just convert the textfield to Render text as HTML!  Put your normal HTML tags in, and it's all good bro.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-03-03-no-work-for-1-week/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-03-03-no-work-for-1-week/</link><title>No work for 1 week!</title><description>Well, last friday (29th) was my last day at Vodafone Group Services.  It feels a bit weird not working there anymore, although I don't even know if it's really hit me.  After 8+ years in the same group of companies it's just a bit strange to be out.I've got a new role at a consultancy based in London, starting with some intensive training on the 10th March.  Should be very interesting to start working on the other side of the consultant/customer relationship.  I'm really looking forward to it - it'll be great to be able to interact with a wider range of companies, industries and perform a much more cross-functional role.  It should be great!  And finally being able to feel like I'm delivering value to people and organisations again - that will be the most rewarding part of the move (of course, I have been delivering value for the past 8 years, it's just in the last 2 it's been in a very different way - all advice and recommendations, rather than something tangible).</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-17-macbook-air-uk-keyboard/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-17-macbook-air-uk-keyboard/</link><title>MacBook Air - UK Keyboard</title><description>Arrrrgggg!When I ordered my MacBook Air the only options I had for keyboard were UK English, and French.  No US English when ordering from the UK store you see.  So, I was trying to hack around with rcov today, and needed to alter some source.  I wanted to copy and edit a line of code, preserving the original.  To do this, I was just going to hash out the line, and put my altered line below.  That's where I encountered my issue.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 17 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-08-coding-vs-configuration-the-vendors-are-missing-the-point-and-the-customers-arent-helping/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-08-coding-vs-configuration-the-vendors-are-missing-the-point-and-the-customers-arent-helping/</link><title>Coding vs Configuration - The vendors are missing the point, and the customers</title><description>Large software vendors do (often in the long term) listen and act on what their customers say they want.  However, implementations are still missing the point.  What customers say they want and what they actually want can be very different things.Historically people (like me) in enterprises have harped on to vendors for years about how we want their large enterprise applications to be more configuration driven rather than coding driven.  The actual purpose behind this was about time to market, resource availability with the necessary skill sets required to maintain and alter the application, effort around testing and deployment, and certainty about the validity of the syntax and sensibility of the customisation.  Vendors have responded by closing the code base, but offering more complex configuration environments - which is exactly what we have asked for (see next paragraph about how we have asked for the changes).  However, what they have provided doesn't meet the actual business goals of the request.  For example, I've been recently looking at some Product Configuration software that has a guided Java coding environment for rules definition.  This doesn't actually make the implementation simpler.  It means that your (previously) relatively unskilled (and that's flame bait if ever I've seen it) configuration staff have to significantly increase their skills to match those of java developers.  Its called "configuration" because its done in a "configuration" tool.  The configuration tool is as much a config tool as Eclipse is (which has code completion BTW, is equally applicable for the task, probably nicer to use and definitely cheaper).  What it's done is moved the effort from the development staff, to the configuration staff.  Assuming staff are happy with what they do, developers are unlikely to want to join a "configuration" team, and configurators are unlikely to want to gain development skills.  One may also argue that your testing and deployment efforts are more difficult, because the coding that was done by people who know how to code, is now done by people who don't know how to code - this in my mind introduces more risk.  You also don't know which parts of the application are affected by this complex configuration activity, and this may drive for more rather than less regression testing.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-08-open-source-is-a-meritocracy/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-08-open-source-is-a-meritocracy/</link><title>Open Source is a Meritocracy</title><description>For those of you unfamiliar with the term...  Meritocracy.CotÃ© from Redmonk quoted the title of this entry in episode 14 of Redmonk Radio.  Again, it's another quote that was like an "Oh yeah" moment for me.  In companies where you produce software (usually) the project timeline or budget is king.  In the open source movement, the best ideas take as long to get implemented as needed - there is no overriding time line that says you must ship that feature by this date.  Also, in distributed projects there can be healthy debate about the best way to implement things - the ideas and implementations with the best merit win.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-04-ouch-googles-response-to-the-microsoft-bid-for-yahoo/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-02-04-ouch-googles-response-to-the-microsoft-bid-for-yahoo/</link><title>Ouch! Google’s response to the Microsoft bid for Yahoo.</title><description>That's some strong language there Dr. Drummond. http://googleblog.blogspot.com/2008/02/yahoo-and-future-of-internet.html</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-30-intervention-multiplies-like-lies/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-30-intervention-multiplies-like-lies/</link><title>Intervention multiplies like lies</title><description>The Economist published a story called "The end of cheap food".It has a couple of interesting quotes:</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-30-requirements-of-charles-schwab/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-30-requirements-of-charles-schwab/</link><title>Requirements of Charles Schwab</title><description>I was listening to a Redmonk Podcast on the train on the way home from work today, and James from Redmonk said something that struck a chord with me.  The quote was...</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-30-time-for-the-big-upgrade/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-30-time-for-the-big-upgrade/</link><title>Time for the big upgrade</title><description>Righto, I've been putting it off long enough.  Got the GiST has been running on rails 1.1.6 almost since it has been launched, and I'd like to take advantage on some of that RESTful 2.0 goodness.  So, I've decided it's time to upgrade it.I've got a couple of issues though.  I currently use (shhhh, I'm about to say a dirty word) Engines to handle my user logins and roles...  They don't work with much past rails 1.1.6.  I also don't have good admin screens on the application, and whenever I need to do maintenance (which is very rare) I need to go and edit the database directly :-(</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-23-automator-automation-of-sending-email-with-attachments/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-23-automator-automation-of-sending-email-with-attachments/</link><title>Automator - Automation of sending email with attachments</title><description>Today I had my first experience creating a VERY simple workflow with Automator.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-18-2-steps-to-happy-tax-in-the-uk/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-18-2-steps-to-happy-tax-in-the-uk/</link><title>2 steps to happy tax in the UK</title><description></description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-18-my-credit-card-says-owie/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2008-01-18-my-credit-card-says-owie/</link><title>My Credit Card says "Owie"!</title><description>Look what I just pre-ordered...</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-10-22-confusing-marketing-messages/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-10-22-confusing-marketing-messages/</link><title>Confusing Marketing Messages</title><description>Sun, what are you up to?Install java to experience the power of java?  What is that supposed to mean?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-10-14-stupid-word/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-10-14-stupid-word/</link><title>Stupid word</title><description>wtf?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 14 Oct 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-06-14-amsterdam/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-06-14-amsterdam/</link><title>Amsterdam</title><description>AMC and I went to Amsterdam to celebrate my birthday this year.  It's an interesting place.  I found the whole experience odd, but enjoyable.  It's a strange mix of people there - I guess we were there for the weekend, so perhaps got the weekend crowds.  There were lots of stags/hens parties, all stumbling around the red light district, being enticed into BananaBar (or whatever it was called) for some live action, and the coffeehuis situation is a bit odd too.  It's quite fun seeing people totally off their chops stumbling around the streets.So, what did we do/see?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-05-25-new-addition-to-the-garden/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-05-25-new-addition-to-the-garden/</link><title>New addition to the garden</title><description>Roll on summer I say.  I just need to hook myself up with some propane, and some meat.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-05-25-poor-analytics/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-05-25-poor-analytics/</link><title>Poor Analytics</title><description>Boots!  What are you doing?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-05-25-off-to-bruges/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-05-25-off-to-bruges/</link><title>Off to Bruges</title><description>I'm taking AMC away for a weekend in Bruges.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 25 May 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-03-13-getting-things-done/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-03-13-getting-things-done/</link><title>Getting Things Done</title><description>(from wikipedia)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 13 Mar 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-02-06-europe-in-2007/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-02-06-europe-in-2007/</link><title>Europe in 2007</title><description>I've been reading The Economist's "The World in 2007" today.  It looks like their predictions for 2007 in economics, business, politics - sort of a what's going to happen in '07.One thing that I just get this feeling about when I read about the political situation in Europe in terms of predictions (and known events) for '07, is that Europe is due some sort of flood of innovation.  I've been seeing and hearing about the Europeans becoming more and more prevalent on the (please excuse the buzzword) Web 2.0 scene, and I just get this sense that something is going to happen this year.  I'd like to think that Silicon Valley buzz will die down, in favour of a Silicon Continent buzz.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-02-06-betavine/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-02-06-betavine/</link><title>Betavine</title><description>(Disclosure: I work for Vodafone Group Services - but I think this is a great idea regardless)Vodafone have launched a new developer community site called Betavine -  http://www.vodafonebetavine.net .</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-02-06-scrubyt-hot-new-ruby-web-scraping-toolkit-released/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-02-06-scrubyt-hot-new-ruby-web-scraping-toolkit-released/</link><title>scRUBYt - Hot, New Ruby Web-Scraping Toolkit Released</title><description>scRUBYt - Hot, New Ruby Web-Scraping Toolkit Released

Peter Cooper over at rubyinside.com has recently blogged about scRUBYt - a new ruby based web scraping toolkit.It looks super-powerful.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-29-political-allegiance/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-29-political-allegiance/</link><title>Political Allegiance</title><description>I've been struggling for a long time to find a party, or ideology that I agree with politically.  I have strong beliefs but I have struggled to find a ideology that they fit within.  Today, I discovered it.I reckon I'm a Libertarian.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-24-mojax/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-24-mojax/</link><title>mojax</title><description>Today, thanks to one of the mailing lists I subscribe to, I learnt about mojax.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-12-lonely-lonely-classes/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-12-lonely-lonely-classes/</link><title>Lonely, lonely classes</title><description>I just had my most pleasant experience with Singletons ever.  I had a little problem I was trying to solve in ruby, and I contacted a friend of mine who is quite a good developer.  He suggested I should be looking at global variables, to static (class) variables, or singletons.  I gave globals a go, and they didn't give me the love I expected, so I said "bye bye" to them - probably never to be used again.  I next tried Singletons.Ruby defines a Singleton module.  This is mixin'd with your code thusly:</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-10-taking-the-vietnam-out-of-iraq/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-10-taking-the-vietnam-out-of-iraq/</link><title>Taking the Vietnam out of Iraq</title><description>Taking the Vietnam out of IraqJenna sent me a link to this story on the BBC web site - it's interesting.  The parallels between the conflict in Vietnam and Iraq are clear to me.  However, an exit strategy for this current conflict needs to be carefully executed.  A cut-and-run is not an option.  The country will be left open, and crippled.  I personally would like the US out of there as soon as possible, not because I have any specific alliance to Iraq, but I just don't think they should be creating and sustaining an unjust and illegal war.  I am an advocate of a medium paced exit, with creation of stability within the country, and leaving it in a state so that it has a good chance of sorting itself out with a positive result.  I don't fancy the chances of a positive result if they just up and leave.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-09-the-apple-iphone-engadget/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-09-the-apple-iphone-engadget/</link><title>The Apple iPhone - Engadget</title><description>How about that.  The rumours were right.  At MacWorld today: The Apple iPhoneIt looks like it will be supporting Wifi, EDGE, camera, GSM, iTunes and has a camera (if you look at the screen shots carefully).  It DOESN'T mention any 3G service, so it looks like video calling will be out, and I assume the camera is on the back (which means it'd be not so cool for video - it's good to have picture in picture so you can ensure you're actually in frame).</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-09-itv-becomes-apple-tv-engadget/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-09-itv-becomes-apple-tv-engadget/</link><title>iTV becomes Apple TV - Engadget</title><description>This is a device I was excited about, but now, meh.  iTV becomes Apple TVNo 1080 High Def???</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-08-bbc-news-entertainment-rem-gain-rock-hall-of-fame-place/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-08-bbc-news-entertainment-rem-gain-rock-hall-of-fame-place/</link><title>BBC NEWS | Entertainment | REM gain rock Hall of Fame place</title><description>The BBC say: BBC NEWS | Entertainment | REM gain rock Hall of Fame place</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-08-sick/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-08-sick/</link><title>Sick</title><description>I'm off work sick today.  It really hit me yesterday, I was feeling so crappy last night, and today is sort of on par, but I get the sense I'm getting better.  Although this does give me the opportunity to catch up on some feeds that I haven't looked at in a bit.I seem to be sneezing a lot, and have runny nose, and a headache, and blocked sinuses.  I put getting sick down to my last couple of weeks of drinking a lot, not eating well and not sleeping much.  I think being generally run down has taken its toll on my immunity, and now I'm paying the price.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-07-verselogic-c2bb-wordpress-openid-plugin/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-07-verselogic-c2bb-wordpress-openid-plugin/</link><title>VerseLogic » Wordpress OpenID Plugin</title><description>I just installed the VerseLogic wordpress OpenID plugin.  This means that you guys (if you have an OpenID already) don't have to explicitly register on my site to comment.  You can just log in with your OpenID, and an account will be created here for you.  No more passwords!You can get a free OpenID at http://myopenid.com/</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-06-wall-calendar/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-06-wall-calendar/</link><title>Wall Calendar</title><description>Now, I don't actually read or subscribe to Martha Stewarts web site, but I found on del.icio.us a link to a Wall Calendar.  This is a calendar that you paint on you wall with blackboard paint (mixed with a number of greys), so you can write on it.  I want to have a blackboard door or area in my kitchen in my new house, so I can write notes up, but a wall calendar is such an excellent idea.Check it out.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-06-sneaky-old-textdrive/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-06-sneaky-old-textdrive/</link><title>Sneaky old TextDrive</title><description>Well, TextDrive have just confused me!  There is an apache_module (I think) that checks for offending strings that are sent to the textdrive servers.  I wanted to (in my last post) explain that I used "wget" to get the RSS feed from my blogspot account, but I figured out that they didn't like me using the phrase "wget" in my previous post.Explanation (kind of) is available here.  Short answer is that the phrase "wget" (minus the quotes) followed by a space is not allowed.  Crazy, huh?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-06-goodbye-blogger-hello-wordpress/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2007-01-06-goodbye-blogger-hello-wordpress/</link><title>Goodbye Blogger, Hello WordPress!</title><description>Well, I've just spent the last wee while migrating my account from http://rickerbh.blogspot.com to http://blog.hamishrickerby.com So, you'll now be reading this on my fancy new self-hosted WordPress instance.The migration process was relatively simple. TextDrive made it a piece of cake for the installation process, I only had a small issue with the migration of my data across.  It was only yesterday that I upgraded my blogger account from the old version, to their new (no longer beta) version, and changed all my templates as well.  Because of this, I couldn't use the automatic import facility on WordPress as it doesn't yet support the new blogger.  I checked out a couple of articles on the web on how to import between the two, but the BEST thing I found to do (and this is suitable for me because I don't really mind that I lost comments on my blog) was export all the articles as 1 large RSS feed, and them import them back into wordpress.  Blogger confused me a little because the default RSS feed didn't support all of my comments, but I found that using the following URL, I could get all the data out that I needed</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2007 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-12-23-value-migration-how-to-think-several-moves-ahead-of-the-competition/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-12-23-value-migration-how-to-think-several-moves-ahead-of-the-competition/</link><title>'Value Migration: How to Think Several Moves Ahead of the Competition'</title><description>(reposted from my entry at allconsuming.net)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-11-15-a-story-about-saturday-morning-cartoons-greatest-hits/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-11-15-a-story-about-saturday-morning-cartoons-greatest-hits/</link><title>A story about "Saturday Morning Cartoons' Greatest Hits"</title><description>What an absolutely fun album.My picks: Liz Phair w/ Material Issue – The Tra La La SongMary Lou Lord w/ Semisonic – Sugar SugarFrente – Let the sun shine inViolent Femmes – Eep Opp Ork Ah-AhDig – Fat AlbertSublime – Hong Kong PhooeyThere were only a couple of tracks I didn’t enjoy, and they were…Butthole Surfers – UnderdogHelmet – GigantorGood stuff.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-11-11-a-story-about-kin-dza-dza/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-11-11-a-story-about-kin-dza-dza/</link><title>A story about "Kin-dza-dza"</title><description>What a strange movie.  With my job I have recently been on a cross-cultural training course, the objective of which was to enable you to understand drivers of behaviour in different cultures.  What was particularly interesting about this to me was the way that the foreigners learnt the strange new culture, and how the changes stuck with them.  And i guess trying to understand (as an observer) what is going thru the foreigners heads.  Perhaps it would have been more clear to me if I lived in the USSR (as it was known) in the 1980’s…Anyway, very good movie, Russian language so there’s a bit of reading for non-russian speakers like me, well worth it.Koo!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-27-i-got-back-in-touch/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-27-i-got-back-in-touch/</link><title>I got back in touch...</title><description>...with a friend from New Zealand a couple of days ago.  I hadn’t heard from or seen him since October 2006, and it was good to hear from him.  I had to do some digging as I had an old email address, but I found a newer one and things are good.ALSO, I’m going to London tonight (assuming I’m feeling better  by mid afternoon) to see a couple of old friends.  One I saw about 6 or so weeks ago, but one I haven’t seen in nearly 7 years.  It’ll be cool to catch up with her again.I really like finding out what people are up to, I think I might have to keep on top of this goal, recontacting people, restablishing friendship – it’s great.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-23-off-to-paris/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-23-off-to-paris/</link><title>Off to Paris...</title><description>...this weekend.  Another one down soon :-)I also went to Malta with work, which was pretty cool.  So, I’m currently at 13%</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-22-more-trips-to-add/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-22-more-trips-to-add/</link><title>More trips to add!</title><description>hehehe.  So, since I’ve joined head office here in the UK I’ve had 3 trips away.2x Dusseldorf (becoming old hat)1x Malta – that was a good trip.  Got to meet some new people, discuss some good technology, and got to go to a new place.  With the addition of this (and my recent trip to Sweden as well) I’ve now seen 13% of Europe.  Got to get that up tho!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-19-a-story-about-pink-floyd-the-wall/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-10-19-a-story-about-pink-floyd-the-wall/</link><title>A story about "Pink Floyd - The Wall"</title><description>I think more bands should be involved with movie production.  You get something completely different with them.  And I’m not talking about “bands” like The Spice Girls, Mariah, or Britney Spears (cause they’ve all made awful movies).This was well worth the watch.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-24-i-just-got-back/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-24-i-just-got-back/</link><title>I just got back...</title><description>...from my new favourite place on earth.  The city is beautiful, the people are beautiful, they dress super well (the place just exudes style), the autumn weather is fantastic.  I had a such a good weekend!  I will be going back to Sweden again.  It’s great.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-24-just-came-back-from/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-24-just-came-back-from/</link><title>Just came back from...</title><description>...Stockholm in Sweden.  Great trip.According to this list I’m 11% of my way through Europe.  I’ve got lots more planned, but nothing new booked.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-18-a-story-about-out-of-nothing/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-18-a-story-about-out-of-nothing/</link><title>A story about "Out of Nothing"</title><description>Good stuff.  I hadn’t heard of these guys before Saturday night (they were playing at my work party – my company rocks in that respect).  I liked them there, and then got some of their tunes.  I’m really quite impressed – how popular are these guys out of the UK?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-02-boring-and-predictable/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-09-02-boring-and-predictable/</link><title>Boring and predictable</title><description>I didn’t enjoy this at all.  I found it quite boring, I felt no suspense, or thrill from it.  It wasn’t scary.  I’m quite disappointed.  There were some very odd shots in the movie, my guess is that they are probably reminiscent of the original.  The reason I say that is that some of the shots felt very hitchcock-esque, and I find often old murder/mystery/thrillers have that sort of feeling.  I will try to watch the original, see if I enjoy that more.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 02 Sep 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-08-31-i-spent-what/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-08-31-i-spent-what/</link><title>I Spent What?!</title><description>When I came to the UK, I lived by myself for about 5 weeks.  In between the going out to experience english culture (read: going to the pub) and working (read: not doing much), I decided that I would implement an application from my to-do list of applications that I want to create.  I put the application that I was writing on hold (and I'll probably start it up again soonish I think) and I set about writing I Spent What?!WTF?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-08-26-a-story-about-solaris/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-08-26-a-story-about-solaris/</link><title>A story about "Solaris"</title><description>I love the empty feeling that space movies often have.  This movie seemed very similar to 2001 in that respect.  Good stuff.  And, of course I love the clean, minimalist, stark interior design of the future.Good movie, now I want to see the original.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-08-01-news-about-caversham/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-08-01-news-about-caversham/</link><title>News about Caversham</title><description>I’m moving here!  It’s pretty big news.On the 20th of August I’m moving out of Newbury, into my new flatshare with 2 others (who seem VERY nice people) in Caversham, Reading.  I’m very excited about it all actually, I get to almost maximise my free company provided accommodation, and then I get to move into a nice, tidy flat, with fun, friendly people.Woohoo!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-23-a-story-about-under-the-table-and-dreaming/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-23-a-story-about-under-the-table-and-dreaming/</link><title>A story about "Under the Table and Dreaming"</title><description>I just found this entire album weak and soulless.  Like they were just playing and singing with nothing behind it.  Obviously I’m setting myself up for some flaming here, but this just was not for me.:-(</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-18-1-week-down/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-18-1-week-down/</link><title>1 week down</title><description>I’ve been living in Newbury just over a week now.  The place seems alright.  The rumors about it that I had heard were much worse than it’s turned out to be.  It’s an old market town in the countryside in england, and it’s just as you expect.  There are some quite picturesque parts of it, there’s lots of pubs, the bars and nightclubs are quite average, and everyone here seems to work for Vodafone.  Food seems expensive, the Thai here is awful, I’m yet to try some fish n’ chips and a curry, but I’ll bet they’re good.  I would like to spend more time here, I’ve met some good people, but I need to find a place to live more permanently, and it sadly won’t be Newbury.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-18-grrrrr/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-18-grrrrr/</link><title>Grrrrr.</title><description>I had a bad experience with a plumber.  In short, he replaced parts of a hot water cylinder that weren’t busted, and left me with no hot water after working at my place for over 4 hours.  I’ve been getting statements from them saying it’s overdue, I’ve called them twice, and they’ve said both times they’ll get the manager to call me back, and they haven’t.  So, I’m writing a letter, with the help of my editing staff and I’ll get my parents to post it (as I’m no longer in the country).Anyway, if you are in NZ I recommend AGAINST using Mr Plumber</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-stickers-medals-or-cards/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-stickers-medals-or-cards/</link><title>Stickers, medals or cards?</title><description>AMC convinced me to do this on my last night in Auckland.  We went uptown from my hotel and found a games arcade that had photo booths – the ones where you can overlay graphics and text on your photos.  The instructions on the machine were poor, and we ended up getting something we didn’t intend to – we got photos on card.We really wanted sticker photos, so we went to another video games arcade that had like 25 of these big photo machines – it was crazy.  We couldn’t figure out which ones of the big machines would make stickers, but we found 3 smaller machines by the entrance, and took 2 sets of sticker photos.The medals reference was for another machine we saw – it would etch your photo onto a piece of metal – I assume to be used as a keyring or something…They are super-cheesy photos.  Great.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-a-story-about-american-psycho/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-a-story-about-american-psycho/</link><title>A story about "American Psycho"</title><description>Phwar!  What a crazy, screwed up book.  I did enjoy it however.  I really enjoyed the amount of detail Bret Easton Ellis went into â€“ the descriptive language is what really did it for me.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-ive-done-it/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-ive-done-it/</link><title>I've done it</title><description>I'm now living in Newbury, Berkshire, England.  I arrived at Heathrow at 6:25 or so this morning, and now I'm here in my new place.  It’s real nice.:-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-ba10/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-ba10/</link><title>BA10</title><description>(see disclaimer at top of previous post!)During the stopover in sydney I felt very lethargic.  I was nearly asleep in the First Class Lounge at Kingsford Smith Airport, but managed to keep myself awake by daydreaming about the new life I'm about to start.  When I arrived in the lounge, I found a seat quickly, as the lounge was quite busy, and I was one of the first off my flight.  I did not want to have to search around for a seat, as having to wait for service, or not being able to find what I expect to be there is one of my pet hates.  I found a seat near the window, but not at the window.  When searching for a seat in an airport lounge, there are 2 key things for me.  Security, and electricity sockets.  Luckily, I usually find what I consider secure and powered seats.  In Auckland lounge I usually have to unplug a lamp, but in other, better equipped lounges, most seats have power and phone jacks built into the "tables" between the seats.  I was sitting near a couple; the wife was clearly South African, and the husband was English.  She was wearing teal tracksuit pants, and a white blouse, and he was wearing black, pleated, dress trousers, and a tweed jacket.  Shocking.  The husband disappeared off and allowed 2 of his colleagues into the lounge, they certainly did not belong in this lounge.  There was a large man who mispronounced "Sudoku"; mispronunciation is one of my pet hates,  The word is su-do-ku, not su-du-ko.  Japanese, like Maori and German, is a very easy language to pronounce.  In Japanese and Maori (and to a lesser extent, German) are always consonant-vowel pairs.  There are also long vowel sounds, as well as the inevitable exceptions to the consonant-vowel rule (shi, n [and in maori nga] for example), but on the whole, they are very easy languages to pronounce.  The other fellow was an Australian/Asian man who thought he was the Sudoku king - he was advising the South African lady on which digits could fit where.  The last part of their conversation I heard was her telling him he was wrong because that box could be one OR eight.In the lounge I consumed a bottle of apple juice, 2 cottage cheese and spinach Filo parcels that were coated with poppy seeds, a roll filled with ham, eggplant, mayonnaise, cheese and lettuce, and a chocolate and raspberry tart.  On the way out of the lounge I took a bottle of Summit Australian Natural Spring Water.Heading towards the plane I contemplated my visa dilemma.  I concluded that if I arrive in England and they will not authorise my visa (as I am 2 days too early) I will enter as a visitor, go to France on the weekend, enter the country again and then they will authorise it, and I will legally be allowed to work in England.  I also had a sense of dread wash over me as I thought about my seat number.  61A.  To me, this did not sound near the front of the plane, nor upper deck.  To my relief, as I entered the plane the steward said to me "to your right and up the stairs sir."  Upper Deck, my favourite place for long haul flights.Seat 61A was one set of seats forward of the emergency exit on the upper deck.  The seat on this flight is facing backwards, which is a new experience for me.  There was a lady in 61B, but she moved because seats 62A and B are free.Predictably, I had the champagne when I arrived at my seat.  The crew up here are friendly and talkative.  After the champagne I had a G'n'T and Kenyan roasted and salted Macadamia nuts and Cashew nuts.  The packaging for the nuts could not have been written by someone with a masterful grasp of the English language.  The package claimed that the nuts were unsuitable for children under 3 years of age (which is OK), but there was an Allergy Alert on the packaging.  There were apparently nuts in this packet of nuts - just in case someone who was allergic to nuts accidentally opened a package of nuts and consumed them.  The nuts and G'n'T were accompanied by a menu.On the menu for a starter was a confit of duck and rocket salad, Green asparagus and artichoke salad, or a fresh seasonal salad served with vinaigrette.  I chose the confit of duck and rocket salad, which oddly was itself accompanied by a fresh seasonal salad served with vinaigrette.  For the main the options were Grilled fillet of beef with horseradish mash and mushroom duxelles, Pan-fried snapper with a red wine jus and baby potatoes accompanied by seasonal vegetables, Fresh pasta with ProvenÃƒ§al vegetables and Stilton cream, or a Main course salad of marinated seafood on fresh salad leaves served with lemon vinaigrette.  I was tempted by both the Pan-fried snapper with a red wine jus and baby potatoes accompanied by seasonal vegetables and the Fresh pasta with ProvenÃƒ§al vegetables and Stilton cream, as I am a big fan of fish, pasta and stilton.  However, I reevaluated how I was feeling, and I eventually chose the Main course salad of marinated seafood on fresh salad leaves served with lemon vinaigrette, as it was the "Well Being" selection, according to the in-flight magazine "High Life".  The salad arrived with six or so baby octopus, olives, beans, rocket, and two large prawns.  It was a very good salad.  It did not however come with lemon vinaigrette, it arrived with 2 containers of caesar dressing, which I certainly did not mind.For dessert the options were a chocolate and strawberry sponge cake, or a selection of cheese.  I again choose the cheese.  The cheeses were a very good, soft, creamy camembert, and an above average strong blue.  The crackers provided were average, being brittle and dry oat based crackers.  Seven below average grapes were on the plate, as well as two celery sticks.  I also ordered a Port and a Coffee.  The hostess poured me the largest port I've ever been served, and then asked about my earring.  She asked if it was in my ear to combat air sickness.  I said, "no, it's just for fashion."  She proceeded to tell me about people how get parts of their bodies pierced as a form of permanent acupuncture.  The pretty hostess then joined in on the conversation, asking if it hurt to get it done as apparently the top of your ear is one of the most painful places on the body to get pierced.  Either I have a very high pain tolerance, or the pierceist I used was very skilled as it did not hurt at all to get the top of my ear pierced.  My nose hurt more when I got that done, but that was also done with a gun, and not a needle.  The nose ring had to be taken out, as the wound never healed and was infected for 9 or so months.  The hostess who initially started the conversation then informed me that she was considering getting the same place pierced on her to help her with dieting, but I just did not understand that and decided it would be best not to pursue that line of conversation further.During dinner the view was spectacular.  The sun had just set over the Great Artesian Basin in the centre of Australia, and the sky colours gradiented from a deep, deep blue, through all colours of the spectrum down to yellow, then red, then the black of the desert.  Now it is pitch black outside.We are now north east of Alice Springs, over the Great Sandy Desert I think.  We are flying at 34000 feet, at a speed of 863km/hr.  I will be in Bangkok in  6 hours and 17 minutes.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-qf190/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-qf190/</link><title>QF190</title><description>(I wrote this on the plane, so things are slightly out of order on my blog...)I'm sitting here on QF190 in business class on my way to Sydney.  I'm reading American Psycho by Bret Easton Ellis.  I love the style of writing in that book.  The level of description for objects of desire and disgust in that book is astounding.  I thought I might write the rest of this entry in a similar style - if you have read the book or seen the movie, let me know what you think.  If you haven't, you should.  Don't think I'm an arrogant mo-fo from this post until you have, and understand the style :-)I did not spend any time in the first class lounge as I ordinarily would as I was spending my time with AMC in the airport, talking.  I also discovered that I am arriving in the UK 3 days before my entry clearance is valid.  That sent me into a panic for 5 or so minutes with associated hot flushes, until we went to the Qantas ticketing counter and talked to the lady there.  I didn't get a good sense of reliability from the advice she offered, which is why I'm going to get Qantas to check it all out from the First Class lounge when I arrive in Sydney.  They already provide me with a greater level of trust than the ticketing counter lady, even though I have not seen or asked them to look into it for me yet.I was the 3rd passenger onboard the plane.  When I arrived in the departure lounge the plane was not boarding, even though the television screens said that it was.  I find that very frustrating.  I could have spent more time with AMC had I known that the plane was not really boarding.  When they called the business class, platinum and gold Qantas frequent flyers, and the One World ruby and sapphire (I think) club members, I had had enough of standing around and boarded instantly.After I had been on the plane for around 10 minutes, I was pleasantly surprised to see that the business class cabin was sparsely populated.  I always like not sitting next to someone whilst I'm flying, and as a platinum  level frequent flyer and paying for a business class ticket they never put me next to someone else, unless the plane is full.  There is one familiar face on the plane.  I do not know his name, but his face is familiar from the First Class lounge from back when I used to fly to Australia weekly.  I was then offered a tropical fruit fusion, a water or a champagne.  I decided on the champagne, as I always take the champagne on a flight, regardless of the time of day.There are 10 people in the cabin.  The capacity is 30.  4 of the people are a party of 3 women, and a baby.  The baby started screaming on takeoff, which always frustrates me.  I expect to hear that back in economy, but not in business.The hostess after take off came around and offered drinks.  My second drink on the plane is always a G'n'T.  This Qantas flight stocks Tanqueray London Dry Gin, which I enjoy.  It is not the number 10, but even the entry level Tanqueray is a good gin.  I decided on a small bowl of olives over the roasted assorted nuts as a snack.  I enjoy the taste of the olives, and have not had them on a plane as an in-flight snack before - they must be a new addition the the menu.  After the gin and olives, the meal service arrived.  The choices were a Thai Style Yellow Chicken Curry with Steamed Rice and Asian Greens, a Salmon Fillet with Herb Butter and Chat Potatoes, or a Salad of Roast Lamb with Chickpeas, Red Pepper and Tomatoes.  The first two items were served with a Peking Duck and Cucumber Mint Salad, and the Salad was served with a fruit salad.  There bread choice was a wholemeal or white bun.  I was drawn by the Thai Style Yellow Chicken Curry with Steamed Rice and Asian Greens, but eventually decided on the Salmon Fillet with Herb Butter and Chat Potatoes.  I felt like fish over Thai Curry, probably because I had a Thai Green Curry for dinner last night.  When the meal arrived, I had the Marlborough Sauvignon Blanc.  The salad dressing was too spicy for the meal, and the broccoli was a little overcooked.  The peas were excellent, as were the potatoes in the Herb Butter.  The salmon was to die for - I have never had such a good aircraft Salmon.  Dessert choices were a Selection of Seasonal Cheese and Dried Fruit, Ice Cream with Almond Biscuits, or chocolates.  I always take the cheese over ice-cream.  The platter consisted of an above average cheddar, and an average Camembert.  The dried fruit was an apricot.  There was also a cube of quince jelly, which I enjoyed.  Then I had a 10 year old Penfolds Port, which was of average quality, a coffee, and a macadamia chocolate.I also drank 3 glasses of water as I need to keep my hydration up because I have been dehydrated over the weekend, and 27 hours in an aeroplane is not good for you.:-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-4k-61a/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-11-4k-61a/</link><title>4K &gt; 61A</title><description>On my flight from Sydney to Heathrow I had a stopover in Bangkok.  As I was going thru the gate to get back on the plane, the machine that reads your ticket made a funny beep, the lady pulled the ticket out, checked the screen and asked me to stand to one side.  She then tapped away on her computer, wrote on my ticket, and said â€œI'm very sorry sir, but your business class seat has been allocated to someone else.  I'm sorry, but we've had to reseat you in first class.â€�  I said â€œOK.  That's alright.  Thank you.  It's really OK.â€�.First class rocks â€“ it was like a 12 hour flight, so being able to lie flat, wearing 1st class pyjamas, with a duvet on the plane was really fun.  The food is better than business class, with more selection.  The chocolates are nicer too.So, that's why seat 4K is better than seat 61A :-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-07-flights-are/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-07-flights-are/</link><title>Flights are...</title><description>...booked.  I leave Christchurch bound for Auckland tomorrow, then I leave Auckland on Monday, and am heading off to London via Sydney and Bangkok.Wow, I'll finally be able to close out this goal :-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-06-well/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-06-well/</link><title>Well...</title><description>I’m very nearly there.  I received Entry Clearance from the British High Commission in NZ here today, so that’s cool.  Now I just need flights sorted and I’m gone.  I’m hoping to leave Christchurch in a couple of days (less than 48 hours), have a couple of nights in Auckland, and then wing my way to sunny Newbury (via Heathrow Airport).  I hope to hear back soon on how we’re going to sort these flights.  They are provided as part of my transfer, and of course, I get to go business class.  And I’m a platinum level frequent flyer, and my points are about to expire – so I’m hoping whichever member of the OneWorld alliance I fly with has the good sence to give me a first class upgrade – you know, for being a good customer :-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-03-rosendahl-alarm-clock/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-07-03-rosendahl-alarm-clock/</link><title>Rosendahl Alarm Clock</title><description>I just bought a beautiful alarm clock.  I wanted a small clock, that I could take travelling, and it needed to be an functional, yet fantastic piece of design work.  So, I was out with AMC + Jenna and stumbled across this fantastic device.  It was designed by flemming bo hansen in 2002, and is made by Rosendahl.It has adjustable snooze, and has a backlit LCD (only when you press on the top) so it won’t keep you awake with the light at night.  It’s a bit pricy, but I consider it a design icon, and it met all of my criteria that I had in mind.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-25-a-story-about-hilary-jackie/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-25-a-story-about-hilary-jackie/</link><title>A story about "Hilary &amp; Jackie"</title><description>I knew of Jacqueline du PrÃƒ© from her music, I'm a big fan of the cello.  I did not however know of the tragic story of her life.  I don't know how much of the movie has been dramatised, but she was a brilliant cellist who was cut down way too early.I really recommend this movie.  I thought it was fantastic.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-17-why-i-recommend-ghost-dog-the-way-of-the-samurai/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-17-why-i-recommend-ghost-dog-the-way-of-the-samurai/</link><title>Why I recommend "Ghost Dog - The Way of the Samurai"</title><description>This movie is amazing.  Brilliant soundtrack by RZA of Wu-Tang fame, some beautiful camera shots, and a compelling story.  I love how Jarmusch has crossed over Samurai code to mafia hit men, and how he shows the dedication that Ghost Dog has for his art, belief structure and warrior code.I really enjoyed it.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-09-grrrr/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-09-grrrr/</link><title>Grrrr.</title><description>I found out tonight B&amp;S are playing in Melbourne tomorrow night, and the night after, and then they’re going to Sydney, and then Brisbane.  Had I known this in advance, I would have been more than happy to fly over to Australia to see them.  Why oh why don’t they come to New Zealand?No matter, soon I’ll be in England and will see them easily (I hope!).</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-09-glimmer-design/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-09-glimmer-design/</link><title>Glimmer Design</title><description>Fingers crossed I can pull it all off.  Time for some marketing I think.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-07-all-arrived/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-06-07-all-arrived/</link><title>All arrived</title><description>safe and complete.  I’m quite happy – very professional movers.Now just got to wait for a letter from VF and the UK Government and I can apply for my entry clearance.  What a long drawn out process.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-31-im-on-the-verge/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-31-im-on-the-verge/</link><title>I'm on the verge...</title><description>Any ideas?</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-23-ive-decided/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-23-ive-decided/</link><title>I've decided...</title><description>...I prefer the mystery of the anonymous subscriber.  It’s nice to know who is interested in what I have to say, but the mystery is more fun.  Of course, that isn’t to say that my readers shouldn’t feel that they can’t make themselves known :-)  I’d love to hear from you.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-22-this-hasnt/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-22-this-hasnt/</link><title>this hasn't</title><description>been going very well for me at all.  I’m moving out of the country soon, and have got rid of virtually everything in my house.  Including, pots, pans, plates, cups, cutlery, fridge + freezer.  So, I can only make food here that IAnd for the last 2, that’s as long as they come in their own containers.I’ve been eating out for around 3 weeks now, I’ve been trying to eat healthy, asian style meals with heaps of vegetables, no added salt or fat, but I’m just not sure of the nutritional value of them.  Oh well, should be back on track next week I think.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-11-im-hoping-this/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-11-im-hoping-this/</link><title>I'm hoping this...</title><description>...is going to be quite easy to achieve.  As part of my relocation, I get shipping allowance.  The allowance is for a 40’ (yes, 40 foot) container to be shipped from NZ to England (which is just about as far as you can actually ship anything) and 30 days storage.  Now, I want to ship 6 pieces of furniture, 2 boxes of books, and 3 boxes of other stuff to Christchurch (about 800 km as the crow flies).  I feel like I’m wasting an opportunity to ship a massive container, but I’ve got nothing that I can’t fit in a suitcase that I want to take…  Maybe I should hire out the space, and ship cars for people.So, this should be easy because someone else is organising it all!  I just have to fill out a form, they come around and pack up all my stuff, and put it on a truck, and then I see it in Christchurch next.  How exciting!Hey, I just realised I mixed metric and imperial measurements there…  Why haven’t the shipping industry caught up to the rest of the (civilised) world?  And why does my mac persist in telling me that it wants things spelt the American way, even tho the language is set to Australian English (there is no NZ).</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-10-why-i-recommend-confessions-on-a-dance-floor/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-10-why-i-recommend-confessions-on-a-dance-floor/</link><title>Why I recommend "Confessions on a Dance Floor"</title><description>I was pleasantly surprised by this album.  I quite liked it â€“ and it's unusual for me to enjoy an entire album of Madonna.  There you go.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-08-arg/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-08-arg/</link><title>Arg!</title><description>My USB controller on my “movies” drive crapped out, so I went and got another one.  Anyway, I’ve now got my media split between the 2 drives – all video on one, all music on the other.  It’s great.  I’ve just got some photos to organise, and my hard drive is officially cleaned up.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-02-gtd/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-02-gtd/</link><title>GTD!</title><description>I've been to the bank, and they were (in principal) happy with me assuming my entire mortgage, and transferring the property into a trust.My lawyer should be delivering me a property settlement agreement today which I need to check, and then the mortgage will be all mine (hang on, that’s not a good thing!).I should also be getting a copy of the trust deed today, which I need to read and accept, and then the trust gets set up.It’s all on.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-02-relocation/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-05-02-relocation/</link><title>Relocation</title><description>company (GMAC) flicked me an email last week.  I need to print it out, sign it, scan the signed copy and email it back to them.  Then they can release my details to all the 3rd parties to start to sort stuff out…  It’s all happening!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-23-got-rid-of/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-23-got-rid-of/</link><title>Got rid of...</title><description>...about half of my clothes (all donated to a charity to raise funds for breast cancer research), and a whole stack of paper from my employer, health insurance, life insurance, banks etc…I feel much lighter because of it.  The relative bareness of my wardrobe is freaking me out a bit.I’m probably going to try to sell my coffee table, my bookshelf, and my large couch (2.5m long, 4 seater) this week.  I have to think about the couch actually.  I don’t know if I want to get rid of it or not.  I really like it, but I’m not going to have a need for it for a while.  I might see if someone I know and trust wants it for a bit.  It’s a very nice couch.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-21-got-me-a-job/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-21-got-me-a-job/</link><title>Got me a job...</title><description>...with Vodafone Group Services, as part of Global IT in Newbury, England.  IÃ¢â‚¬â„¢m starting on the 15th May.  Quite quick really.  I think IÃ¢â‚¬â„¢m going to be doing telecommunications system design for 18+ countries or something.  ItÃ¢â‚¬â„¢s a pretty big deal for me actually.  IÃ¢â‚¬â„¢m very pleased.Should be out of Auckland sometime early May, and in the UK around the 10th of May I think.  HavenÃ¢â‚¬â„¢t got flights yet.  ThatÃ¢â‚¬â„¢s all part of the organisation around the transfer that I havenÃ¢â‚¬â„¢t got done yet Ã¢â‚¬â€œ IÃ¢â‚¬â„¢m waiting for Group to get the written confirmation of my acceptance and then the transfer company apparently contact me.Woohoo!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-18-omg/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-18-omg/</link><title>OMG</title><description>They were AMAZING.  I was completely astounded by the show.  Amina were fantastic too.  I was completely blown away by the whole experience.  Next place I plan on seeing them in Iceland.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-11-sorted/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-11-sorted/</link><title>Sorted</title><description>All done!  Took way longer than I expected.  I got my photos at Photo Warehouse, and then went up to the AA here on Albert St.  Then I waited for about 20 minutes in the “Licensing” queue, only to discover to get an internationl drivers permit I go to the information counter.But, it’s all done now.  I don’t need it for the UK, but any other european country I drive in will want me to have it – it’s more of a just-in-case type item.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-got/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-got/</link><title>Got...</title><description>...my tickets.  All set for 17th April in Auckland.  How exciting!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-easy-peasy-but-ill-still-complain/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-easy-peasy-but-ill-still-complain/</link><title>Easy Peasy - but I'll still complain</title><description>It only costs me $20, and a passport sized photo.  All the information that a New Zealander needs is available at the AA.  However, I will make one complaint – the AA charge you $20 to go in and process it manually in store, $30 if you post it in (cause of course its more expensive for them to open an envelope rather than have the entire infrastructure of a building for me to wait in), and $40 to handle an online application, where I do all the work (scanning drivers license, and photos), and they just print the stuff out – they receive the data on a file server, and don’t even need to open an envelope.Way to embrace the digital age, slackers.  That sort of stuff just makes me angry.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-i-purchased-a-nas/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-i-purchased-a-nas/</link><title>I purchased a NAS...</title><description>...on the weekend.  Quite a good one I think (good price point)So, at the moment all my media is being transferred over to it, then I’m reformatting my 200Gb HD into HSFS, and moving the DVDs that I have back over to it.  Then I’ll have a dedicated music server on my NAS, and my movie drive as a portable disk.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-i-am-doing-this/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-10-i-am-doing-this/</link><title>I am doing this...</title><description>...in anticipation of an imminent move overseas.  I’m such a geek – I made a gantt chart of everything that I need to sort through, and have given myself activities for every night this week.  Which reminds me, I better get off my computer and start sorting through my clothes – that’s the activity for tonight – I must be ruthless.I want to move 13,000 miles away with only 2 suitcases, and perhaps a carry on bag, laptop bag and a suit bag (or 2) as well.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-05-why-i-recommend-freakonomics-a-rogue-economist-explores-the-hidden-side-of-everything/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-05-why-i-recommend-freakonomics-a-rogue-economist-explores-the-hidden-side-of-everything/</link><title>'Why I recommend "Freakonomics : A Rogue Economist Explores the Hidden Side</title><description></description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-05-hero/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-04-05-hero/</link><title>Hero</title><description>I saw this â€“ I don't remember if I added it, or if Jenna added it.  Anyway, this was one of the most beautiful movies I've seen.  Absolutely stunning.  Visual masterpiece â€“ my eyes were hardly worthy.  The soundtrack is perfect as well.It appears that it was pretty windy in China 2000 years ago â€“ their hair is always blowing around whilst they are fighting ;-)I thought the story was actually a bit weak, and in some places I found it a bit difficult to follow.  The concept for the story was OK I guess, but the execution was a little poor IMHO.  However, the stunning camera and scene work more than made up for it.Based on the visuals and soundtrack alone I recommend it.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 05 Apr 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-30-battle-royale/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-30-battle-royale/</link><title>Battle Royale</title><description>Ah, the Japanese.  Great electronics, crazy english translation, even crazier movies â€“ well, that's not usually true, but Battle Royale is certainly one of the crazier Japanese movies I've seen.  It has more blood that Zatoichi, and it certainly more Japanese (although that's an odd comment, given Zatoichi was about a Samurai â€“ hmmm),  Anyway, I enjoyed this movie â€“ it's certainly action packed.  The only part which annoyed me a bit is some of the dialogue â€“ it's very stereotypical of what I would expect Japanese early teen conversation to be â€“ but I guess the movie is about Japanese teens.  Maybe I was expecting too much in the dialogue front â€“ or perhaps it was a case of engrish on the translation.  Anyway, I liked it.And now there's only 46 left on the list.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 30 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-29-not-new-but/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-29-not-new-but/</link><title>Not new but....</title><description>...It's new to me.  Given the recent hype because of the movie, and the fact that a couple of my friends are really into him, I thought I should check out Johnny Cash.  In my usual style, I've gone way overboard.  I've got hold of the following albums.American 3American 4American RecordingsAt Folsom PrisonAt San QuentinLove, God, Murder [2cd]Man In Black (54-58) [5cd]Man In Black (59-62) [5cd]UnchainedUnearthed [5cd]So, I'm going to be all cashed out at the end of this I suspect.  I've listened to American 3 so far.  I give it a 3/5.  One and Won't Back Down are the best tracks there IMHO.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-29-a-little-disappointed/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-29-a-little-disappointed/</link><title>A little disappointed...</title><description>I used to be a massive fan of Concord Dawn.  The hard, industrial feeling dnb that they used to churn out.  This album is not to my tastes.  It's alright, but it's not great.  My favourite track is Say Your Words (and only the 2nd half of it â€“ that's the hard type of dnb I like).  I give the rest of the album a â€œso soâ€� rating.  Apart from Say Your Words, the other tracks I thought were OK were Breathe, Broken Eyes, Blow, Never Give Up On Love and Don't Have To Run.So, I'd say if you're a fan of the older Concord Dawn, I wouldn't recommend this album to you.  If you like Shapeshifter, or that general friendlier dnb â€“ smoother, more rolling â€“ then I'd say give it a listen.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-22-why-i-recommend-v-for-vendetta/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-22-why-i-recommend-v-for-vendetta/</link><title>Why I recommend "V for Vendetta"</title><description>Good movie.  Yet again, I got to go to a preview before official release in New Zealand through a guy at work (his partner is the Marketing Manager [or something] for Village Roadshow â€“ so I often get free tix to sneak previews).  I really did enjoy this.  It's got some cool special effects, I like the concept of the story (deep down I'm sure there's a conspiracy theorist/activist in me somewhere), and of course, it's got Natalie Portman in it.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-13-couple-of-movies-on-the-weekend/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-13-couple-of-movies-on-the-weekend/</link><title>Couple of movies on the weekend</title><description>I watched Last Days and The Dinner Game (aka Le DÃƒ®ner de cons).Last Days was the most boring movie I've ever watched.  Most boring EVER.  Boring.  I was so bored.The Dinner Game was much better.  I watched the french with english subtitles version.  It was a bit of a cheesy comedy, but clever cheesy.  I really enjoyed it actually.Jenna claims that she didn't add Last Days to the list, that it was an addition from me.  Perhaps that's right.  I can't blame her for wasting 97 minutes of my life.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-13-adaptation/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-13-adaptation/</link><title>Adaptation</title><description>Very clever movie.  I enjoyed it, but only for the concept of the movie, and the cleverness that was used in unfolding what the movie was actually about.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-good-little-piece-of-relatively-experimental-electronica/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-good-little-piece-of-relatively-experimental-electronica/</link><title>Good little piece of (relatively) experimental electronica</title><description>Good stuff on this vinyl.  The reason why I got a set of Dntel is because the guy collaborated with another guy for â€œThe Postal Serviceâ€�, whom I absolutely love.  I think the story goes that the Dntel guy did the tracks, and the other guy did the vocals â€“ or perhaps the other way around.  Anyway, Vynalogica 1 is pretty good.  The 2nd track features vocals, the 3rd is relatively experimental â€“ but very good.  It reminds me a bit of Mum or Boards of Canada in places, and the vocal track is quite Postal Service.Recommended.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-its-ok-but/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-its-ok-but/</link><title>It's OK, but...</title><description>...only 3 stars from me.  The album just didn't gel with me like I expected it to.  I haven't listened to any of Isobel Campbell's music outside of B&amp;S, and I guess I was perhaps expecting something different.The music coupled with Mark Lanegans vocals struck me as very Nick Cave-esque.  It could have just been because they have similar voices.Anyway, I didn't find anything particularly exciting about this album.  I'm going to listen to it a couple more time though, to give it a fair go.  I really do want to enjoy Isobels music.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-dntel-day/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-dntel-day/</link><title>dntel day</title><description>This is a fantastic album.  If you are a fan of postal service, then it's highly likely you will love this too.  I think I have a new addition to my favourite bands.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-great-track/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-07-great-track/</link><title>Great track</title><description>This vinyl is essentially the single track â€œLove Generationâ€�.  It fantastic.  I haven't rated this 5 because of the relatively boring b-side remix of Love Generation by Mugwump.  Not so impressive.  But get this just for the a-side.  Top.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-04-a-story-about-kung-fu-hustle/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-04-a-story-about-kung-fu-hustle/</link><title>A story about "Kung Fu Hustle"</title><description>Got this out yesterday (I also hired The Experiment and Ripleys Game â€“ so they'll be watched soon).This movie is fantastic.  I don't believe I've ever laughed at a single movie so much.  It was the cheesy lines, and ridiculous stereotypes that made me laugh.  There is some mighty impressive fighting (as you'd expect), and some astounding special effects.Anyway, I really enjoyed this â€“ and recommend it to all.  I wouldn't say it's a good introductory movie to the martial arts genre (because of the westernised cheesy-ness â€“ it might give you the wrong impression for the rest of the genre), but if you're into that scene it's great.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-03-got-me-some-new-dgs/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-03-got-me-some-new-dgs/</link><title>Got me some new D&amp;G's</title><description>I got one of the girls I work with to come out sunglasses shopping with me last week.  Went down to a parallel importer on queen street, and they didn’t have anything I was interested in.  I wanted some more fashionable glasses, not sports styled glasses.  I already have some adidas ones, but I felt I needed a change.So, into Sunglass Hut on Queen Street, have a look around, and I get very confused.  I found it very difficult to determine which glasses are for which sex – there are some obvious female-themed glasses, but the mens ones are more difficult to distinguish.  So, I speak to the clerk, and she gets me out quite a few pairs.Long story short, the first pair I try on are the best.  D&amp;G 2075’s.Nice.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-03-thursday/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-03-03-thursday/</link><title>Thursday</title><description>I went out last night and talked to a relative stranger for about 4 hours.  Was good.  I’m sure the wine helped :-)  Actually, it was probably the good social skills of my poor victim.  I usually struggle to make small-talk – I shouldn’t really be belittling the conversation I was having by calling it small talk.  It wasn’t small.  It was talk, chat, get to know you kind of stuff.  I really enjoyed myself.  Might do that again.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-26-auckland-museum/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-26-auckland-museum/</link><title>Auckland Museum</title><description>Went to the Museum here today.  I was astounded.  It is so very good.  I've been living here for just over 6 years now and had never been.  My mate Dave asked me if I wanted to go to see the Da Vinci machines exhibition and I am quite keen to see that.  Anyway, I met him down at Santos (a local cafe), we had a late lunch, bit of a chat then made our way down to the Auckland War Memorial Museum.  We arrived down there at about 3.  After a quick chat to the guy who was taking the $5 donation to get in, we discovered that the line for the exhibition was about 1 hour long...  So, we decided to have a look around the rest of the place then check out the line again.  It's a very good museum.  Anyway, we were having a look around, about a 1/3 of the way around the 3rd floor they announced that the place was closing in 5 minutes.  We didn't even get to see the whole place.  Anyway, I'd be quite keen to go back, and the Da Vinci machines closes on the 5th of March.  It has late night on Wednesday, so perhaps that's a plan for after work.I've gotta check out more places of cultural significance in this city.  I think next on the list will be the Art Gallery.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-19-a-review-of-morningwood/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-19-a-review-of-morningwood/</link><title>A review of "Morningwood"</title><description>hehehe.  I really enjoy rock bands fronted by women (eg, elastica, garbage, veruca salt), but have only really listened to british chick rock, not really american.  I understand Morningwood come from New York, they are a 4 piece rock band with a female singer.My favourite 2 tracks off this album are â€œNth Degreeâ€� â€“ which is the single I heard on Juice here (one of our MTV-type channels) and â€œJetsetterâ€�.The music has a very new wave and punk type feel about it â€“ which kind of explains why I like it so much.  Also, Nth Degree (for me at least) has a similar feel to some of the Saint Etienne tracks off Good Humor.Anyway, I'm super impressed by these guys.  I hope they get the airplay they deserve.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 19 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-18-calexico/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-18-calexico/</link><title>Calexico</title><description>On my trip to wellington last weekend Johnny (the younger brother of a friend I was staying with) suggested I might want to check out Calexico.  I got a hold of 2 of their albums, one is a joint effort with Iron and Wine (who I also really like a lot), and the other is Calexico alone.If you're into folk guitar type sounds (Iron and Wine, Belle &amp; Sebastian [twee pop â€“ but a similar sound]), Sufjan Stevens etc) I can highly recommend In The Reins.  The album Feast of Wire was a more interesting mix, which I'm lead to understand is more core Calexico.  Jazz, Afro-Latin, and acoustic guitar blend with beautiful voices to create a masterpiece.  I'm quite impressed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-18-at-canterbury-university/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-18-at-canterbury-university/</link><title>At Canterbury University</title><description>I had to do a first year paper in data structures and algorithms.  I scraped through, I just could not “get it”.  I’ve decided that Haskell (Hugs is what we used) is not going to conquer me.  I am going to relearn and understand functional programming.Now the slacker kids get to use Java.  They aren’t forced to learn the joy that is functional/declarative programming.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 18 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-07-interview-went/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-07-interview-went/</link><title>Interview went</title><description>quite well I felt.  They have already organised for me to speak to the “Group Resourcing and Talent Management” (of course, I am talent!) liason again.  He started asking about visas and everything, I was a bit unclear about my situation.  I found out as I was walking home that my grandfather was born in South Africa (I always thought he was born in Newcastle).  However, because of South Africas relatively late independence, and a change in immigration law in the UK, I might still be able to swing a visa thru him or my father.  Anyway, the company indicated that it would be no issue to hook me up with one.  I just can’t be in the country when they file the application.Fingers crossed!  Looks promising!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-05-a-bit-weak/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-05-a-bit-weak/</link><title>A bit weak</title><description>That's how I found it.  The album left me feeling quite empty.  Like I hadn't really been listening to anything.  The only track I actually enjoyed off the album was â€œBlack Girlâ€�, and I think the reason for that was because I really like the Nirvana acoustic version â€œWhere did you sleep last nightâ€� from their Unplugged album.I was recommended this album by a friend, and she's not usually wrong about music that I'll like.I was quite disappointed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-04-interview/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-02-04-interview/</link><title>Interview...</title><description>on Tuesday night.  Fingers crossed.  I have to do a video conference, and because we (in NZ) are 13 hours ahead of the UK at the moment, I have to be in at work at 9pm.  I’ll be heading in late in thr morning on Tuesday I think.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-31-background-sorted/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-31-background-sorted/</link><title>Background sorted</title><description>I’m a big fan of the Art Nouveau movement – organic forms, writhing plants, all that sort of thing.   The backlash by art against the industrial revolution and all that…  Anyway, my background for my phone sort of reflects that.It’s actually a piece of art produced by the good lads from Sigur Ros.  Whilst not strictly Art Nouveau, it was a multi-media production (photos modified with Natural products), and has a feeling and emotion about it that I quite like and can identify with.  Please see it below.I’m actually really keen to get my powerbook acid etched with some sort of vine and leaves motif, but am a bit worried about getting it wrong.  I really don’t want a horrible looking powerbook.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-30-lord-of-the-flies-peter-brook-1963/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-30-lord-of-the-flies-peter-brook-1963/</link><title>Lord of the Flies - Peter Brook (1963)</title><description>Just saw this movie, I'm really making an effort to power thru Jennas list.  Going quite well so far I think. Anyway, this movie had the 2nd most boring intro ever, the first being the 4mins+ of black screen that comes with 2001: A Space Odyssey.  The movie itself was alright I guess, for 1963.  The cinematography was OK, Peter Brook managed to portray the savagery of the boys quite well, especially in the nighttime scenes.  The fast camera work, shots of fire sparks, all the noise and blurry shots added to the atmosphere. One thing I loved was how english they were at the start of the movie.  The language is what I find particularly interesting.  It's the same as the Narnia books by C.S. Lewis â€“ all very old sounding.  I grew up reading that sort of stuff, and I just like the idea of that sort of â€œproperâ€� behaviour. I haven't actually read William Goldings book that the movie was based on, I somehow managed to skip that at school.  Maybe that'll have to be my February book Only 53 movies left to see.  I should be able to close out another three by this Saturday.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-22-bdo-auckland-woohoo/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-22-bdo-auckland-woohoo/</link><title>BDO Auckland - Woohoo!</title><description>I made it.  It was fantastic.  Saw lots of bands, got a little messed up, got home very late, got to sleep much later. Pictures of this at http://flickr.com/photos/rickerbh/tags/bigdayout/ My favourite acts that I saw:
P-Money â€“ amazing mixin'n'scratch'n.  I didn't even plan on going, Yanti convinced me.
Franz Ferdinand
*2 Many DJs Fantastic day â€“ thanks to Sarah, Steve, George, Johnny, and Yanti for joining me :-)  I had a blast.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-17-bdo-this-friday/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-17-bdo-this-friday/</link><title>BDO this friday!</title><description></description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-16-got-me-some-new-shoes/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-16-got-me-some-new-shoes/</link><title>Got me some new shoes</title><description>Shoe Science came thru.  Even delivered early.  I only went in yesterday morning, and the correct size arrived for me this morning.  What service!  Anyway, I just tried them out.  The salesgirl in the store suggested I run about half of the usual distance I run for in them, as I need to get used to the different shoes.  They certainly are more comfortable than my last “running” shoes, and my legs don’t hurt now either.  Top.  If you’re interested, they are the Brooks Adrenaline GTS 6.  Blue and silver.  Not that nasty yellow and silver.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-15-coffee-cigarettes-jim-jarmusch/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-15-coffee-cigarettes-jim-jarmusch/</link><title>Coffee &amp; Cigarettes - Jim Jarmusch</title><description>I just watched this movie.  Enjoyable.  Again, I didn't know what I was getting myself in for.  I knew it was going to be black and white, but that's about it.  I found the first couple of scenes to be a bit odd.  I quite liked the scene with Jack and Meg White and the Tesla Coil, but my favourite had to be RZA, GZA (of Wu Tang fame) and Bill Murray.  I thought that was hilarious.  I also quite enjoyed the tie ins from scenes to other scenes.My favourite quotes â€“ please forgive me if I don't get them 100% â€“ it is from memory:</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-14-scope-creep-part-2/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-14-scope-creep-part-2/</link><title>Scope, creep. Part 2.</title><description></description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-14-shoe-science-is-the-biz/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-14-shoe-science-is-the-biz/</link><title>Shoe Science is the biz</title><description>Back from my shoe shopping excursion.  My mate Kurt said I should go down to Shoe Science and get fitted for a pair of shoes.  It’s quite interesting how they fit you.  They have this camera and a DVD recorder, and a little running track.  You run up and down the track 3 times, and they record your legs running.  Then you watch the video, and check out the ankle movement.  They then can choose a shoe that will correct your ankle roll.  The theory is that the shoes you get from there will be biomechanically correct, and they will lower the chance of injury.Anyway, I found some shoes that corrected my ankle roll, and they didn’t have the perfect size for me.  They are ordering them in, so on Tuesday (or perhaps even Monday afternoon) I’ll have some new running shoes that no longer hurt me.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-13-ipod-battery-replacement/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-13-ipod-battery-replacement/</link><title>ipod battery replacement</title><description>This afternooon I didn't have that much to do at work.  I also received my ipod replacement battery kit today.  I thought I'd replace the battery, and document how it went.   As usual, pics available at flickrIn the kit I received a set of instructions, 2 nylon "screwdriver" tools, and a new 850mAh battery suitable for a 3G ipod.With the tools you have to wedge them between the white and shiny metal casings, in the centre of one of the longer sides.  This is more difficult than it sounds.  It's very important you use nylon tools, as metal tools will scratch and possibly dent your ipod.  This took a couple of go's, and I ruined one of the tools ends while I was at it.  The kit suggested you resharpen the ends of the nylon if you did this.  Luckily, I didn't ruin the 2nd tool, and got the cover prised off.Next step was to pull the hard drive out.  The ipod hard drive is connected by a little socket connector mounted on a piece of copper.  It just pulls straight off.This is just a shot of the ipod open - hard drive not yet removed.Hard drive removed - the black box is the old batteryTo remove the battery, you just pull out the little connector.  It comes off easily.  The wire for my battery was pushed under the mainboard, so required a bit of movement to be removed.  The battery then comes out.To fit the new battery, it was quite important that I thought about the orientation.  My new battery has longer and thicker wires than the original, so placement was important.  I had to get the wires back under the mainboard, then fold the cable over so the connector could get back into the socket.Hard drive goes back in - no dramas whatsoever.  Well, getting the connector back on was a bit fiddly, but it only took about 15 seconds for me to sort it out.It's quite important how the cover goes back on as well.  You have to be careful not to catch the new battery wires in the cover or you could break the wires.Complete!</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-got-my-replacement-battery/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-got-my-replacement-battery/</link><title>Got my replacement battery</title><description>My 3rd Gen ipod is just over 2 years old now.  I’ve abused the poor battery a lot, and now it has a life of about 1 hour.  I went on http://www.trademe.co.nz and found a replacement battery kit for a 850mAh battery (apparently 30% more capacity than OEM battery).  the kit comes with a battery, instructions, and 2 nylon tools for prying the thing open (so you don’t scratch the case).  I’m going to replace the battery tonight I think – of course that depends if I go out for drinks after work.  I’ll be documenting the replacement on my blog I think.  I’ll keep you all posted.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-donnie-darko-directors-cut/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-donnie-darko-directors-cut/</link><title>Donnie Darko - Directors Cut</title><description>Frickin brilliant.  I loved this movie.  I knew nothing about it going into it, it was on the list and I spotted it first at the movie store.  The score is so good â€“ I have a nice home theater system and Franks voice kept coming out behind me, freaked me out.  There are some intensely beautiful scenes in this movie â€“ I'm quite a fan of beautiful movies.  The concept of the story is excellent, the end where everything ties together was perhaps a touch predictable â€“ but then again I seem to have a knack for picking the twists in movies (I picked the twist in â€œThe Usual Suspectsâ€� about 30 minutes into the movie), but it was thoroughly enjoyable. 9/10.  I was torn between 9 and 10 of 10. 9 down, 57 DVD's left.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-jennas-list/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-jennas-list/</link><title>Jenna's list?</title><description>My friend Jenna is doing an Honours degree at the university of Canterbury.  She is taking some film papers, and seems to be quite a cinemophile (did I just make up a word?).  When I was down there she was shocked at the lack of movie watching I did, so I committed to her that I would watch a list of movies that she's given me.
FWIW, the list is here.  If there's a movie you think should be on it, let me know and I'll pitch it to her for adding.
http://rickerbh.tadalist.com/lists/public/186249</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-w00t/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-12-w00t/</link><title>w00t.</title><description>I’ve created a file parser in racc.  Boy, way to overengineer a solution for my problem.  That was totally unnecessary, but I feel I now know an immense amount more about syntax and parsing.  I think I’ll call this complete.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-10-wtf-is-racc/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-10-wtf-is-racc/</link><title>wtf is racc?</title><description>racc is the rubyised implementation of lex/yacc.  I want to learn this as I've got some file parsing that needs doing, and this is the proper way to parse files.  It's a lot of guesswork at the momentâ€¦
Check http://i.loveruby.net/en/projects/racc/ to see what I'm on about.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-09-scope-creep/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-09-scope-creep/</link><title>Scope, creep.</title><description></description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-09-cameraphone-repaired-armed-and-ready/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-09-cameraphone-repaired-armed-and-ready/</link><title>Cameraphone repaired, armed and ready</title><description>I got my Nokia 6230i Cameraphone back today.  It had been at the repairshop.  I’ve reconfigured it so that I can send pictures I take with it wirelessly via GPRS to flickr.  I can take good looking pictures (well, 1.3MP – better than my old VGA cameraphone) whereever I am.  Now, I’ve just got to start using it…</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-08-product-development/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2006-01-08-product-development/</link><title>Product Development</title><description>There are some things I need to do as well.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2006 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-29-select-with-value-rubyonrails/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-29-select-with-value-rubyonrails/</link><title>select with value - rubyonrails</title><description>Grrr, just spent a little while playing with the "select" form tag in rails.  Pain in the ass.  The issue I was having is that I want to give users an option of 2 values with a default selected value on the "new" form.  I also have a edit form that I want to let users update their objects with, and again, only 2 values.  These values are static, and I didn't want to have the pain of creating a db table, and an object to represent it.  That would result in unnecessary code, and unnecessary database hits.The issue with the "select" tag is that I cannot determine how to set the selected value, without using a collection of objects.  I had a look for a solution for this problem, and found this site.  This gave me a helper that lets me put in an object, with some methods to get the value and text options for my option set.  that was alright.  But, I didn't want the full object model to be supported.  I was after a very simple implementation with using a hash, and a string as the selected value.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-28-drinking-and-hospital/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-28-drinking-and-hospital/</link><title>Drinking and Hospital</title><description>Last night I picked Sarah up from her Mums place, and we went round to Jenna's place.  We started on some wine, and ended up playing some drinking games.  We decided to jump the fence at the botannical gardens in christchurch, and go drinking in there.  We did that, I snapped some good nighttime pics - available as always on my flickr site.  I had a good time.  Sarah then decided that she wanted to leave, and I walked her back to Jennas to get her stuff and a taxi for her.  Long story short, she spiked her leg on the fence and we ended up in A&amp;E at Christchurch Hospital.  We stayed there for about 90 minutes, then Sarah went up and asked how long the wait was going to be.  There was a sign we had missed, and it said there was a 6 hour average wait.  Seriously, there were like 10 people waiting - and 6 hours!  I found that absolutely shocking.  Anyway, we packed that in, and went to the 24 hour clinic - Sarah had to pay, but didn't wait 6 hours.  She got 5 stitches.Crazy night.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-26-fire-service/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-26-fire-service/</link><title>Fire Service</title><description>I went out to the Christchurch International Airport today, and got to see the fire engines...  There are about 5  big engines down there.  Got to go for a ride on one of the runways in the fancy new engine - $1.2m purchase price, around $300k commissioning cost.  It carries around 10k litres of water.  The main water cannon can shoot water up to 70 metres.  VERY impressive.  I got to control the cannons - that was quite cool.  They were surprisingly responsive.  There are a couple of joysticks - one for the nose mounted cannon, and one for the top mounted one.  Very good.The new truck has around 680hp, and weighs 33 tonnes.  It has quite good acceleration given its weight.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-26-bbq-at-andy-and-jeanettes/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-26-bbq-at-andy-and-jeanettes/</link><title>BBQ at Andy and Jeanettes</title><description>Went out to Andy and Jeanettes (Mr and Mrs Barrett) tonight for a BBQ and some beers.  They got a new BBQ a wee while ago with some department store vouchers they got from their wedding.  Nice BBQ actually - 4 burner masport thing.  So, we christened it - it hadn't been used before.  It was also Andrews first time (I think) as chief BBQ'er - he did a good job  for his 1st time.  He discovered that if you have crumbed food on his BBQ, you need oil :-)</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-25-xmas-day/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-25-xmas-day/</link><title>Xmas Day</title><description>I arrived at my parents place at around 8am.  My sister was the only one up.  I quickly downed some panadol, and went and had a shower.  I could feel the headache coming on.Basically, we after this, we had breakfast, opened some Xmas presents, went to my Grandpa's place to pick him up to bring him back out to the farm.  After we got back out here, I went for a bit of a nap.  Zzzzzz.  Slept till lunchtime.  Ate waaaaaaayyyyy too much food.  After this, we drank Cognac and Brandy, and then I went for another nap.  Got up again at 7pm, watched some figure skating on TV, and now back to bed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-24-xmas-eve/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-24-xmas-eve/</link><title>Xmas Eve</title><description>Went to Jennas place today.  Her friend Amy who was up in Christchurch from Timaru came over.  We headed to the Dux and caught up with another friend of theirs, Becky.  The dux was so busy - completely packed out.  Only stayed there for one beer, then we went back to Jennas place for more drinks.  Eventually a whole stack of people came over, we polished off bottles of Whiskey, Vodka, and Gin.  Met a bunch of new, fun people which was great.  I'll post the pics to flickr.Got to bed at about 3:30am - 4am - not quite sure really.  I got up at around 7:30am to get my ass back to my parents place for Xmas.  The roads were dead that early on Xmas day.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-19-go-paypal/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-19-go-paypal/</link><title>Go PayPal!</title><description>Woohoo!  I got PayPal IPN integration working.  Now you can register with my application, make a payment via PayPal, and PayPal will come back to my web app and let me know that you've registered.  Clever stuff.I used the PayPal IPN GEM from http://dist.leetsoft.com, and integrated it with my own Payment object.  I don't really have the need for a full "ordering"-type system with my application.  There is only ever 1 line item per order, so only a single payment object is required.  I could have implemented an order, with order_line_items, and shipping and billing addresses, and tax and handling calculations, but I don't need them.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-17-money-ruby-on-rails-and-aud/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-17-money-ruby-on-rails-and-aud/</link><title>Money, Ruby on Rails and AUD</title><description>I had a bit of a play with the Money and Paypal GEMs available at http://dist.leetsoft.com .  The Money API only supports Euro, US and Canadian dollars.  For my paypal integration, I need to support Australian dollar (as dirty old paypal don't support NZD).  So, I've extended the Money class to create an AUD implementation.  There's nothing special about it, but if you're too lazy to write the couple of lines of code yourself, here it is.Also, I've been having a bit of trouble getting the Money and Paypal GEMs to work.  The issue is that from within a rails controller it doesn't recognise the Money or Paypal classes.  It can't find them.  This is the only GEM that I'm having troubles with.  My solution was to import the .rb files into the /vendor directory.  If anyone has this problem, or has a solution for this problem - or even tips, please let me know.  It's annoying me now.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-12-hey-been-out-at-pub-quiz-this-evening-tomas-an/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-12-hey-been-out-at-pub-quiz-this-evening-tomas-an/</link><title>Hey. Been out at pub quiz this evening. Tomas an...</title><description>Hey.  Been out at pub quiz this evening.  Tomas and me.  We got last.  We suck so much.  Lost by 5 points.  Couldn't answer any of the first 7 questions - bloody current affairs, and local sports.  Why do I pay so little attention to local sports.  It's really because I just don't care about how local team x is going against foreign team y.  Proletariats and their distractions I guess.  And then we stayed for the open mic night.  First lady was depressing, 2nd dude was alright.  3rd dude was this freaky modern beatnik poet - so random.  4th was this dude who was quite good.  last we saw was this lady who's stage demeanor was equivalent to that of Jewel.  She was a really good singer too.  I['d buy her CD if she released one.Tomas and Jon went off to the Drake.  I went home.  I've got a conference call with VFUK in the morning (urrrg, 7-am) about a job.  Fingers crossed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-10-every-days-a-saturday/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-10-every-days-a-saturday/</link><title>Every day's a Saturday</title><description>Had lunch with my friend Brodie today...  We went to De Fontein at Mission Bay.  Had a good talk about what's going on with me.  It was nice to see her.  I think when I leave NZ I'll go to Sydney for a couple of days and catch up with Matt, Brodie(the Matt in that pic ain't the Matt I reference before) and  J.  Will be nice to see all of them before I leave this part of the world.Good progress on the job front last week.  Promising feedback from a couple of people.  Fingers crossed.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-06-ive-started-a-little-collection-of-lifestyle-fas/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-06-ive-started-a-little-collection-of-lifestyle-fas/</link><title>I've started a little collection of lifestyle, fas...</title><description>I've started a little collection of lifestyle, fashion, design and architecture links in del.icio.us.If you're interested, check it out.  Nice products, nice design.  I'll add to it as I find fun new products.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-05-odd-ive-never-noticed-this-before-now-that-i-h/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-05-odd-ive-never-noticed-this-before-now-that-i-h/</link><title>Odd, I've never noticed this before. Now that I h...</title><description>Odd, I've never noticed this before.  Now that I have it's obvious.I got some food out of the freezer before to cook for dinner, I closed the freezer, and it started hissing at me.   "ssssssssssssss" it was saying.  I thought that was a bit strange, and opened it to see what was creating the noise, and the noise stopped.  I closed it again, and it started to make the noise again.  About 1/4 of a second later I concluded that this was the sound of air getting inside it.  This is the obvious bit, but had I not heard it, I would not have thought about this ever.  When I open the freezer, warmer air from the kitchen gets inside, raising the temperature of the freezer.  When I shut the door, the warmer air cools down, and the molecules vibrate less, and the air "contracts".  This leaves a vacuum, which air from outside the fridge comes and fills - I'm assuming because of possibly dodgy seals on the fridge.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-05-ahhh-being-the-sheik-geek-that-i-am-i-love-tokyo/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-05-ahhh-being-the-sheik-geek-that-i-am-i-love-tokyo/</link><title>Ahhh, being the sheik geek that I am, I love Tokyo...</title><description>Ahhh, being the sheik geek that I am, I love TokyoFlash.  And their latest is to die for. Saishin Diode Watch @ Gizmodo </description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-05-there-is-a-windows-equivalent-of-dashboard-its/</guid><link>https://hamishrickerby.com/posts/2005-12-05-there-is-a-windows-equivalent-of-dashboard-its/</link><title>There is a windows equivalent of Dashboard. It's ...</title><description>There is a windows equivalent of Dashboard.  It's called Konfabulator.  And before I get any mac nerds telling me how different Dashboard is, and how dare I compare it to Konfabulator - I don't care.And it has a family guy RQG - well, at least it has Stewie - but he's my favourite character anyway.</description><author>&lt;a href="/about"&gt;Hamish Rickerby&lt;/a&gt;</author><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2005 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate></item></channel></rss>